English sub from www.OpenSubtitles.org
翻译 校对 中文轴 后期: Ericartman
西绪弗斯公司出品
是时候逃离
生死存亡的关头
不 这不是游戏
只是新的开始
珊农·莱托
这张专辑是关于
This record is about
克服挑战的
overcoming challenges.
为自己坚信的事情而斗争
It's very important to
是很重要的
fight for what you feel is right.
托莫·米利舍维奇
我们被逼进了死角
We were backed into a corner.
对我们来说 不成功 便成仁
For us, it was all or nothing...
有时候我们必须
Sometimes you have to
杰瑞德·莱托
为自由而战
fight in order to be free.
<全面开战>这张专辑
"This Is War" is an album
是关于斗争的
about conflict.
我们迎来了一场大战
We had a huge battle
对方是我们的唱片公司
with our record company.
这张专辑就纪录了
The album kind of documented
我们生命中
this really turbulent time
这个混乱的时期
in our lives.
唱片公司与艺人之间
There has always been a serious
总是有这么一种相当严重的
distrust between an artist
不信任关系
and their record label.
我从没听过有哪家唱片公司
I never heard of a label
是不坑艺人的
that doesn't screw an artist.
商业模式就是这样
That's the business model
靠坑艺人来赚钱
is screwing the artist.
乐队里谁也没想过
None of us in a band ever dreamed
我们会如此幸运
that we would be so lucky
巴塞洛缪·卡宾斯 导演
能取得这样的成功
to have the success that we've had.
但现在
Now here we were faced
我们所拥有的一切
with the possibility
又都面临着
that everything was gonna be
即将被剥夺的境地
ripped right away from us.
3年前
全面的经济风暴
There is a kind of economic
正在酝酿
perfect storm brewing
情况很糟糕
disastrous situation
他们快要失去工作!
they're losing their jobs
油价上升
rising gas prices
朋友们 美国同胞们
My friends and fellow Americans,
我很高兴
I am very pleased and
也很荣幸地 向你们介绍
very privileged to introduce to you
下一位美国副总统
the next vice-president of the United States:
萨拉·佩林州长
Governor Sarah Palin
来自杰出的阿拉斯加州!
of the great state of Alaska.
洛杉矶
军号嘹亮
You can hear the bugles blaring.
羌管悠悠
The sound of the battle cry.
战鼓擂擂
The march of the drum
惊醒吾眠
calling me from my slumber,
起身赶赴
pushing me toward
朝阳 战场
A new day. A new fight.
噢 哇.. 噢 哇...
Oh wow... Oh wow...
太他妈亮
It's too fucking bright.
JL:这是2008年
It was 2008, we were on the road
我们已经巡演了2年
for over 2 years and had recently
刚刚回到洛杉矶
returned to Los Angeles to work
来制作我们的第三张专辑
on our third album.
摸爬滚打了10年
After over a decade of struggling,
我们终于有了点突破
we finally had a breakthrough
取得了些成就
and achieved more success
这是我们想都不敢想的
than we ever dreamed.
我们的第二张专辑<美丽的谎言>
Our second album A Beautiful Lie
售出了超过350万张
sold over 3,5 Million copies
我们也因此有机会进行全球巡演
and gave us the chance to tour the world.
我们都为人生的这段历程
We were all incredibly excited
激动不已
about this time in our lives
于是决定把新专辑的制作过程
and we decided to make a film
拍成一部电影  然而...
about the next album but...
突然一切都变了味
It quickly turned into something else.
30秒上火星被起诉赔偿...
Thirty Seconds to Mars is being sued for...
3000万美元！挺萌的吧
30 Million Dollars! Cute! Right?
今夏 该乐队的唱片公司 维京/百代EMI
This summer, the band's label Virgin/EMI
以违约之名
filed a breach-of-contract suit
起诉了30秒上火星
against Thirty Seconds to Mars.
而Jared却坚称
However, Jared insists
乐队只是在行使其合法权利
that the band was just exercising their legal rights.
莱托在乐队网站上回应违约诉讼
他们要啥？
What do they want?
电台DJ
三千万美元
30 Million Dollars.
真的咩?
Really?
"我们卖了200多万张
专辑却没拿到一分钱
是不是难以置信..."—JL
你被要求赔偿 三千 万 美元！
You're being sued for 30 Million Dollars
前EMI传媒创意服务部 副部长
这你...呃...
What are you?... Huh...
晚上怎么睡得着觉呢
How do you sleep at night?
维京/百代要求30秒上火星
赔偿$3000万 莱托回击
我不知道这个数字是怎么来的
I have no idea where the number came from
除了...
other than...
前EMI首席财务官
这肯定不是为了媒体炒作而瞎说出来的
It certainly wasn't a wink to the press or
不然也不会用这个数字
were we clever to use the same number...
百代唱片(EMI)找到了盈利新方式：
起诉自家艺人.
30STM的专辑十分热销
Thirty Seconds to Mars have just sold a lot of...
三十秒上火星乐队 律师
卖的很好 但他们却没赚到钱
a lot of albums and never made any money.
我们也没想着赚什么大钱
We weren't really expecting a bunch of money
三十秒上火星乐队 主唱
我们只是觉得奇怪
we just thought it bizarre that...
专辑得到了这么大的收益
that all this revenue was being generated
但我们却仍然负债270万美元
and that we were still 2.7 Million Dollars in debt so,
于是我们进行了调查
we started to look into it.
30STM的合同
30STM suffered a
三十秒上火星乐队 经理人
甚至并不是
contract that really wasn't even
直接与EMI签的
a direct contract with EMI,
这是个垃圾协议
it was bad deal.
他们说的意思 就是让我们闭嘴
They basically told us to shut up
赶紧去做下一张专辑
and go make another album.
他们没有回应
They weren't addressing our concerns
三十秒上火星乐队 鼓手
我们对于合约的质疑
that we had with the contracts,
所以我们决定终止跟EMI的合同
so we decided to terminate with EMI.
我们签了9年
We've been signed for 9 years.
但根据加州法律
Under California law, you can't be held
超过7年你就可以单方面解约
bound to a contract for more than 7 years
这一条在法院 我个人 以及我们大家看来
which the courts and myself
还是挺合理的
and we all feel is pretty reasonable.
杰瑞德·莱托回击EMI 暗示有黑幕
援引劳动法条款
2008年7月4日 我们向EMI递交了解约书
On July 4th 2008, we sent a termination letter
我们援引了“7年条例”
to EMI. We sighted the 7-year statute
从而合法地解除了我们与该公司的合同关系
which legally ended our contract with the company.
2008年七月4日后 我们将不再隶属
任何诉讼来讲
With any lawsuit,
前EMI旗下 Capitol音乐集团董事长
都有双方的说法
there is two sides of the argument.
你方的说法是:
Your side of the argument was:
"我们的合约不再有效了
"Our contract is no longer valid
"因为'7年条例' "
because of the 7-year statute"
他方则说:
and their side of it is:
"不 这是不适用的
"No, that is not applicable.
"你承诺了制作若干唱片
You have a commitment based on a number of albums,
"我们也投入了相应的资金
based on the amount of money we've spent
"你不能单方终止"
and you're not free to terminate this."
这真是个大卫对战歌利亚的故事(以小战大)
It really is David against Goliath
作家、音乐记者
在这个案件上 唱片公司这个巨人歌利亚
and... and in this case the label,
打出了这个3000万美元的诉讼
the Goliath was well, here's a 30 Million Dollars lawsuit
"我要让你夜不能寐" 他们不...
like I am just gonna keep you awake, they don't...
他们自己不会因为打这个天价官司..
It doesn't keep them awake
..而睡不着觉 他们就是:
suing for 30 Million Dollars, it's just:
我要在精神上和财务上把你搞垮
I'm just stress you out, you know, emotionally
直到你投降
and financially until you cave.
诉讼第1天
3000万美元
30 Million Dollars.
嗯
Yeah.
我觉得 这疯了吧
I think, it's so crazy
我都搞太不明白啊
that it doesn't even really register with me.
怎么就特么 这么大个天文数字
Like it's so fuckin' like just fantastically huge
这都让我 不明白啊
that I don't really get it.
你想想 就算咱赢了
You would hope that, in success,
他们会不会主动来改条款:
that they would even take the initiative to be:
"好了 你们看,
Okay look, you guys,
"你们签的合同确实够糟糕,
you have the worst record deal on the planet.
"咱们来改一改
Let's make this right
"我们也知道 总有一天
because we know at some point
"你们自己会明白过来
you're gonna educate yourselves,
"你们会知道你们受到了剥削
you're gonna realize that you've been stolen from
"你们受到了要挟."
and you've been hijacked.
他们才不会那样
They don't do that.
不会
No.
他们会让艺人找他们改
They make the artist do that
他们才不管什么公平合理
and they don't want to do what's fair, what's right,
你得拿法律武器震慑他们
You have to threaten them with legal actions,
你制造审判先例 来震慑他们
you have to threaten them with creating precedences
这样才能从他们那儿得到
in order to get them just to make
些许公平 尽管他们仍然能够
a slightly fair deal that still leaves them
分到绝大部分的利润
with the complete lion share of everything
而且依然能完全掌控
and the complete domination
三十秒上火星
of Thirty Seconds to Mars.
乐感 是人类在子宫里就产生
Musical taste actually begins to form in the womb,
神经学家 <音乐中的大脑>作者
在胎儿时期就完全形成了的
the developing fetus has a fully functioning
在20周的时候就有完善的听觉系统了
auditory system at 20 weeks and is hearing
可以听到环境中的所有声音
all of the sounds of the environment.
音乐无处不在
Music is everywhere.
真是丝丝渗透进我们每日的生活当中
It's really woven into the fabric of everyday life.
感知研究显示,
Perceptual studies have shown that,
前EMI旗下 Capitol音乐集团 首席执行官
在较高的人类需求层次中
in the higher hierarchy of needs,
人们最关心的两件事就是
the two things that people care most about,
音乐和性
are music and sex.
所以毫无疑问
So, there is no question
音乐是一项首要需求
that music is a primal need
拥有难以置信的能量
and it's unbelievably powerful.
没有其他的艺术形式像音乐一样
No other art form works like music.
音乐制作人
绘画很美丽
Paintings are beautiful
但你懂的 一旦你看到它
but, you know, once you see it
最后你总会获知其表现的所有内容
eventually you see everything in it.
但音乐不同 它是不断变化的
With music, it's forever changing.
一件音乐作品要想成功
For a piece of music to succeed,
就要能够让你进入
it has to take you through
某种情感的历程
some kind of emotional journey.
正确的和声序列
The right chord sequence,
歌曲的时间编排
the right few seconds of a song
都要体现出来
and you are right there.
我就是这样感觉的
That's exactly how I feel.
我喜欢尽力去诠释出
I love in trying to interpret what
一首音乐 在词和曲双方面的内涵
the music is saying both lyrically and musically,
这就是为什么我爱音乐
that's why I like music
当我读懂的时候
and once I've tried to figure it out,
我的内心会充满狂喜
I have personally crazy fantasies of what
想象音乐人在写歌时
the person was thinking about
是怎么想的
when they wrote that
他们为什么写这首歌
and why they wrote that
以及它与我的关联
and how does it relate to me.
这就是音乐
That's what music is.
你正确地把握了时间 歌词
You mix the right word at the right time
这样歌曲就以一种美妙
with something that's beautiful
感人的方式
and moving and sort of.
梦魇乐队 主唱
这让你感到
That makes you, you know,
汗毛都立起来了
the hair on the back of your neck stand up,
真是个难忘的时刻
it's an incredible moment.
我想这就是为什么我们需要音乐
That's probably why we need it
因为它太美好了
because it's wonderful.
一首歌有它的故事
The song has a story in it,
有它的心脏
there is a heart behind it,
音乐人/技师
其中有频率
there is a frequency within it
有作为人类的思考
and you, as a person, delivered it
因此人们才在乎音乐
and that why people care.
音乐是全世界最强大的媒介
Music is the most powerful vehicle in the world.
没说的
Period.
尽管有诉讼
Despite the lawsuit,
我们还是决定要继续
we decided to move forward
开始做我们的新专辑
and start making our new album.
这就意味着 要我们自己出钱
And that meant financing it ourselves.
于是我们在好莱坞山房子的地下室里
So, we built a studio in the basement
建起了录音室
of the house in the Hollywood Hills,
雇来了Flood 开始了制作
hired Flood and began the process.
Flood就像是 音乐制作人中的巨星
Flood is like this superstar producer.
传奇人物 他制作了那么多的
A legend. A guy that has made albums
经典专辑
that will live forever.
20年来 我一直在听他的作品
I mean 20 years I've been listening to his work.
我常常翻到一张专辑、CD、录像带的背面
I used to look on the back of albums and CDs
看到 "这个Flood是谁啊？"
and tapes and who is this guy Flood?
我都不知道这是不是人名
I didn't even know if he was a real person.
因为只能看见这么个神秘简短的名字 Flood
You always see this mysterious little name Flood.
他制作了Depeche Mode乐队,
He produced Depeche Mode.
U2.
九寸钉
Nine Inch Nails
波莉·简·哈维
PJ Harvey
...碎南瓜的专辑
Smashing Pumpkins
当然 以及最重要的 显然是
and the most important, obviously, is:
我们三十秒上火星 所以...
Thirty Seconds to Mars, so...
他极富创意
His wide range of creativity,
鼓舞人心
it's inspiring.
对我来说 创意就是 弱点 与冒险
For me creativity is about vulnerability, taking risks,
音乐制作人
融入真实的情感
showing one's true emotion
让每一个艺人都切身感受到
and to be able to make everybody feel as though
他们可以犯错误
they can make mistakes,
可以不顾一切
they can put themselves out there
不会有人相互指责
and there's no recriminations.
Jared冒了很大风险
Jared took on a huge responsibility
肩负重担 他选择不与唱片公司合作
and a huge burden when he chose to start making
独立制作<全面开战>
"This is War" without a label on board.
他也不知道乐队的前景会怎样
He didn't know what the future held for the band.
这很可怕
It was very scary because
他当时跟我说:
he was letting me know like:
"你看 只有咱们自己
"Look, we are alone.
"不会有外部资金
There ain't gonna be any money coming in,
"不管是咱们作为乐队 还是我个人
whatever we, as a band, or really me, Jared,
"作为乐队领袖 在乐队过去的收入中攒下的钱
as like the leader, did good business to save some of the money that we made,
"这都不够咱们做专辑
that's now going to pay for our album
"和请制作人和工作人员的
and our producer and our studio
"这最后很有可能变成 0美元（破产）"
which may result in zero Dollars."
我们只能全靠我们自己
We had to bet on ourselves,
用赌城的行话来打比方,
even using Vegas terminology:
好像我们就是黑色方格
it's like if we are the black square,
我们把全部身家押到黑上
we put everything on black and
然后掷骰子
we roll the dice.
诉讼第14天
我们要去 见我们的经理人Irving Azoff
We are heading to see our manager Irving Azoff
和我们的律师Peter Paterno
and our lawyer Peter Paterno.
你好吗
How are you doing?
好
Good.
好吧 你想怎么样
Okay, what do you want to do?
我想的就是:
What I would like to happen is:
我想上法庭
I would like to go to court,
我想站在由我的同行组成的陪审团面前
I'd like to sit in front of a jury of my peers.
我觉得就算是最无争议的诉讼
I think in any lawsuit that's a slam-dunk,
乐队经理人
还是有20%的几率会出问题
you still have a 20% chance you get screwed.
我先问个大方向的问题
Let me ask you a big picture question:
跟传统的唱片公司签约...
Signing a record deal with a traditional
还是不签？
record company or not.
有没有别的选择?
What are the other options?
我的意见一向是
My view has always been that any deal that
跟小厂牌公司签的合约
doesn't involve a major record label is better
比跟大厂牌公司签约要好
than any deal any major label will offer you,
因为你有自主权 自己说了算
because you have your ownership, you're masters.
其他的事也是一样 你得记住
The other issue too, that you have to keep in mind,
就算你跟别的公司
is that even if you signed
签了合约
with one of these other alternatives,
EMI还是要告你
EMI is still suing you.
看来咱们的情况不容乐观
It seems that we're between a rock and a hard place.
要么签个恐龙时代的超级老套合约...
Either signed some antiquated dinosaur deal.
但是 就没有新模式吗？
But what's the new model of it?
新模式更差
The new model is worse, so the antiquated
恐龙级超老合约 还是可行的
dinosaur deal is a good deal.
为什么没有更好的新模式？
Why there isn't a new model that's better?
听音乐的人前所未有的多啊！
People are listening to music more than ever.
因为我们都在赔钱
Cause they're all losing money.
他们不买
They're not buying it.
他们也许听了
They may be listening but
但他们不买
they're not buying it,
乐队律师
他们不付钱
they're not paying for it.
这样（音乐）甚至更不值钱了
It makes it even less valuable.
如果我们面对的是传统的唱片公司
If it were a traditional record company
还用坐在这儿干嘛
we wouldn't be sitting here,
早就解决了
we would have settle that a long time ago.
但现在时运不好
We drew a bad card.
咱们面对的是一个外行
We drew a guy from outside the business
他不按行业规矩来
who doesn't play by industry rules,
他也不在乎
who doesn't give a shit.
不能跟他们调解？
We can't get them to settle.
他们现在不会跟咱调解 他们跟我说:
They're not gonna settle now. They said to me:
"我不管这官司打多长时间
"I don't care how long it takes.
"不管别的唱片公司多么生气
I don't care how angry it makes the other label groups.
"我都要求开庭审理"
I would go to court to a decision."
唱片产业处在一个非常非常不利的境地
The record business is in a very very serious trouble.
看看历史上那些已经消失的行业
If you look at historically other businesses
你就会知道
that have gone away,
我认为它就是在逐渐的衰退
I think there is this kind of gradual decline...
呃 不是"逐渐" 其实衰退得挺厉害的 像这样
Well gradual, it has been pretty severe, but like this
然后它遇到了一个拐点
and then it just reaches a kind of tipping point
于是就跳水了
and just falls off the cliff.
唱片产业的盈利模式
The economics around the record business
就是卖专辑
is based on selling albums.
洛杉矶KROQ电台  音乐总监
你知道 小时候 你必须得买下整张专辑
You know growing up you had to buy the entire album
才能听到里面你喜欢的那首歌 不买不行
to get the song you loved, you had to!
没别的办法
You had no choice!
而现在却是
And now, what happens is:
孩子呆在家里 说:
A kid is sitting at home and goes:
“我一定得听Kings And Queens这首歌”
"I've got to hear that Kings and Queens song,
“一定要听”
I got to hear that!"
他们不用去开车 或是求父母
They don't have to get in a car or ask their parents
攒上个12块钱才能去买
and save up 12 bucks to go buy.
现在你有了选择
Now you're given a choice and
你可以只买你爱的一首歌
you can buy the song you love
不用买整张专辑 你会选哪种呢
without buying the album, you gonna do that,
这都不止 你甚至可以 免费得到
not only that, when you can buy... Have it for free.
音乐消逝的十年：销售额减半
唱片的销量 在过去的六年里
Record sales have dipped 20% a year
每年都减少20%
for the last 6 years, now.
这极为严重
That's a lot.
音乐产业真的遭到了重创
The music business has really become decimated
很大一部分原因就是人们都去非法下载了
and it has been largely because of illegal downloads.
当然也有别的因素
Others factors too.
但我们面临的环境就是
But the predicament we're in now, is
整整一代的音乐听众
that an entire generation of music listeners,
基本上所有21岁以下的人群
virtually everybody under the age of 21,
从小到大
has grown up in a world
从记事起
where, for their entire sentient lives,
在他们的世界里 从没为听音乐花过钱
they've never had to pay for music.
而当他们看到我这个年龄的
And they look at people my age and
买专辑的人 他们就认为我们真傻啊
who buy music they think we're saps.
“你为什么要花钱买免费的东西？”
Why would you pay for something that's free?
“这就跟花钱买空气一样啊！”
It would be like paying for air!
"林肯公园"乐队主唱
我记得好像是Trent Reznor说过:
I've heard someone like Trent Reznor say:
(注: Nine Inch Nails九寸钉乐队主唱)
"你知道 你辛辛苦苦花了一整年做这个
"You know, you work for a fucking year on something,
"投入了这么多时间 这么多钱
and you put all this time and you spend all this money
"用来创作...这些歌
on creating these songs
"然后你买杯咖啡 却比这歌还贵"
and a cup of coffee buys you the day, cost more than your song."
消费者不会走进食品店
Consumers wouldn't walk into a grocery store,
然后偷一条面包 据为己有
and steal a loaf of bread and have it
但偷音乐就没事
but it became okay to steal music.
这真不是唱片公司的问题
That really isn't something you blame the labels for,
你懂的 这是科技
you know, that's technology.
System of a Down乐队主唱
唱片公司从来没能有力地凝聚起来
The labels have never been cohesive enough to create
建立他们自己未来的分销渠道
to create their own future distribution systems.
所以才让一家电脑公司抢了先
Which is why it took a computer company
建立了iTunes 嗯.. 而如果他们(唱片公司)够聪明
to start iTunes, Have they've been smart enough
他们自己也能联合建立类似iTunes的音乐渠道
they would have co-owned their own digital delivery
(iTunes)真是把一切都搅乱了
like iTunes, you know, that was a big mess up.
当苹果公司——它是个很棒的公司
When Apple, which is a great company,
别误会——它是美国第三大的公司
don't get me wrong, is the third largest company in America
也是美国最大的音乐经销商
and the biggest music retailer in America,
我觉得这才是人们担忧的
I think that's concerning.
它生产的不是音乐 而是设备
It's a device manufacturer.
唱片公司被惊呆了 也吓坏了
The labels are petrified and terrified.
他们不明白怎么回事
They don't know what's going on,
他们都搞不懂自己的行业了
they don't even understand their own industry anymore,
他们规模太大 发展太慢 所以...
they've been too big and too slow to change, so
我觉得它们势必有一天会瓦解
I do think they're just gonna start to crumble.
诉讼第30天
咱们开始Kings And Queens吧
Let's play "Kings and Queens"...
里面肯定有点问题
There is definitely something in there,
再来一次
let's try it again.
我觉得就是这段   -我也觉得
I think this is the part (I think so too)
我坐在那儿 在脑海里唱着
I'm sitting here... I'm singing it in my head.
充满感染力 我还想听这样的片段
It's infectious, I want to hear it again.
那个吉他声放出来 我是说...
That guitar creeping up... I mean...
好哎 对
Great. Yeah.
我知道 做这样的专辑,
So, I know, for making records like this,
工作量很大 很难 这都是必经之路
the hard work, the struggle is all part of it,
重点是你们要忠于自己的感觉
it's about being truthful to yourselves.
我觉得现在就是这样
That's what I mean about now.
你可以跟着感觉 拥抱它
It's like you can take it and embrace it.
把它展现出来
And go with it.
失去点平衡 疯狂一下
Be a bit off balance, try out a few mad things
你们现在的状况完全可以
and there you are in a great place to do that.
在这期间
In the middle of all this,
我们收到了一条好消息:
we got some good news: we were nominated
我们得到了拉丁MTV音乐奖的提名
for a Latin MTV award.
于是我们打点行装 飞到了墨西哥
So we packed our bags and flew ourselves to Mexico.
我们正在工作室里努力...
同往常一样激动
内心充满热情与快乐 终于能够制作新歌了
我是Flavor Flav(演员) 我旁边是Tomo 还有其他的哥们
Flavor Flav here with Tomo, and the motherf******* boys.
如假特么的包换！
The real f**king McCoys!
虽然大家都说俺们是明星
Even though everybody classify us as stars,
但俺们是从三十秒上他娘的火星来的!
but we are 30 Seconds from Motherf******g Mars
过了一个超级兴奋 难忘的夜晚
After an exciting and unforgettable night,
我们醒来发现 我们收到了
we woke up to discover that we had been served
EMI的法律文书
with legal papers from EMI.
EMI要求我们提供所有邮件 所有文件 所有的样歌
所有的歌曲思路 2008年7月4日前写成的 所有歌词
被告 杰瑞德·莱托和珊农·莱托 官方又称
三十秒上火星
他们现在想查我们的电脑 我们的...
...硬盘 我们的黑莓手机 查找任何有利于他们的信息
现在的势头就是 他们要赢 我们要输
管理人员
现在不是对错的问题 也不是发展 成功 的问题
我想知道是整个公司都这么想
还是只有公司高层？
是新的人员进来了 说：“好了 咱们的问题在哪？”
而这是困境之一
他们就是想要摆脱困境
你一定要理解 整个事
You have to understand this whole story
是完全发生在我们新专辑制作之前的
really began before we started the album.
在我们成为被告之前
Before we got sued,
我们还与EMI有着友好的谈判关系
when we were in friendly renegotiations with EMI.
谈判进行的很顺利
And that was going well,
Irving(经理人)在与他们协商
Irving was talking to them.
我们达成了一些成果
We had met some efforts to address some commercial
前EMI首席财务官
与30stm达成了一些商业协议
terms of the Thirty Seconds to Mars agreement
这些协议 我们回头想想
that I think, we all recognized,
可能是...不太合适
were probably inappropriate.
然后 就出了问题
And then, something happened.
谈判没戏了 出于各种原因吧
That effort stalled out for whatever reason.
再过不久 投资人就要连
Soon investors won't be able
甲壳虫乐队的歌也买不起了
to buy a piece of the Beatles.
百代EMI下个月将变为私有制
EMI is going private next month.
该英国音乐出版商将被收购
The British music publisher is being acquired
价格高达近50亿美元
for nearly 5 Billion Dollars.
泰丰资本成功竞购EMI
泰丰资本 是一家位于英国的私募股权投资公司
Terra Firma is an UK based private equity company.
专门收购陷入困境的公司,
They tent to buy companies that are distressed,
这些公司并不一定来自陷入困境的行业
not necessarily companies that are in distressed industries,
这一点对于EMI的案例很重要
which is important point when you come back around EMI.
如果你是英国人 你一定会这样想EMI:
If you are in England, I imagine you look at EMI:
它是甲壳虫乐队的老家
it's the home of the Beatles,
它是英国最为标志性的公司
it's is one of the most iconic British companies ever.
你会对自己说: "哇 我肯定也能把它弄好,
And you say to yourself: "Wow! I can fix that too.
"那帮蠢材 他们肯定不懂经营"
Those dummies, I'm sure that they don't know what they're doing either.
"所以 我把它买下来好了 让它起死回生"
So, let me buy that and turn it around."
泰丰资本的真正的领导者是Guy Hands
The real principal of Terra Firma is Guy Hands,
葛涵思 泰丰资本创始人
他基本上掌控着泰丰资本的运营
he's essentially the guy who runs Terra Firma.
Guy Hands是个白手起家的亿万富翁
Guy Hands, he is a self-made billionaire.
他真是难以置信的成功
He's been incredibly successful.
音乐产业作家
他有一次成功 是
One of the victories he had was
他买下了北欧一条高速公路上所有的加油站,
he bought all the gas stations on a highway in northern Europe.
然后把里面的洗手间 都清洁一新
And he cleaned the bathrooms.
他们清洁过之后 突然
Once they cleaned them all of sudden
加油站的生意就突飞猛进
business went up at the gas stations,
附带的便利店也是日进斗金
at the convenience stores attached to them.
于是他就赚了大笔的钱
And he made a ton of money.
他们花几十亿美元来收购一个公司
They spent billions of dollars on a company
我认为 他们是真的坚信
and I really think that they believed
自己可以将之扭亏为盈的
they could transform it.
葛涵思的泰丰资本
泰丰资本介入并收购EMI之后
When Terra Firma came in and purchased EMI
泰丰资本24亿英镑收购百代EMI
就开始了他们的扭转机制
they became that benefactor regime
让我们赔3000万块钱
that sued us for 30 Million bucks.
泰丰资本把我们从谈判桌上拉走
Terra Firma took the negotiation away from us.
我想他们是了解了这个事 然后说...
I think they looked at it and they said,
我想他们不满意的是
I think they didn't like the fact
我们在友好谈判 这个事实
that it was a friendly renegotiation.
他们先入为主地认为 我们肯定不是省油的灯
They came with a perspective of we've got to be hard-nose.
录音 第一次
Take one...
我起调没起好 再来一次
I'm in a bad beginning... And again...
喔~~ 热起来了呢 哥们 再来一次
Woo... It's getting warmed up, dude, one more.
好极了
Perfect
咱再录2次
Let's just do a couple of more
然后听听
and then we'll listen
再一次
One more...
一次 最后一次 再来嘛...
One last one... One Maaaas...
等一下 我放松一下手
Give me one second to loosen my hand up
再一次... 好玩嘛
One more... Just for fun.
哥们 你还没到一百次呢
Dude, you're still under a hundred takes.
现在是97次
You're at ninety seven.
97次? 好吧 妹的
Ninety seven? Okay. Fuck that!
咱再来三次
We're gonna do three more.
好的 来吧
Yes! Come on!
等一下 我还没好呢
Hold on... Let me get ready...
我从没遇到过 如此有动力
I never met anyone as driven
如此辛勤工作的人
who will work this hard
他会为了工作 你懂的
who will go to the, you know,
赴汤蹈火
end of the earth and back,
就算只有百万分之一的机会也在所不惜
just on a one and a million chance,
只要是对音乐有好处
that something is gonna help the music.
我认识的人里面 没有人
There is nobody, that I know personally,
能真正说 对自己的艺术 自己的工作 如此用心
that can say that they do for their art and their work
像他一样
what he does.
你问我 Jared在<全面开战>
You ask me what Jared's role is
中是何种角色?
in the making of This is War?
这个题目就太小了
It's too small of a question
无法涵盖他在30STM世界里所做的工作
to encompass what he does in the world of Thirty Seconds to Mars
他是乐队的灵魂
He is the Mastermind.
即便是现在这样的成就
Success on the level that we even have right now
也是我们从来不敢想的 你无法...你怎么能想得到?
we never dreamed. You couldn't... How could you dream of this?
我和我哥出生在路易斯安那州
My brother and I were born in Louisiana.
我们趟过密西西比河泥泞的岸边时
We climbed out of the muddy banks of the Mississippi
一手拿着乐器
with our instruments in one hand
另一手攥着满满的 食物救济券
and... A fist full of food stamps in the other.
我们的妈妈十分年轻
We had a very young mother.
我想 她怀着我
I think she was pregnant with me and
带着我哥的时候 才18岁
had my brother by the time she was 18.
我还是个孩子的时候 就有了孩子
I was a child that had children.
我从没觉得有什么艰难
I never considered that any of it was difficult.
带着两个宝宝去上学
Going to school with two babies and
领着救济金 靠着食物券
being on welfare and having food stamps
杰瑞德和珊农的母亲
和医疗补助卡过活
and Medicaid cards.
小的时候 家里穷
When you are a kid and you're poor,
你也意识不到
I don't think you realize it.
直到我长大了
It wasn't until I got much older
我才发现我们没钱出门
I realized we didn't have money to go out
买很多礼物
buy a bunch of presents
每到圣诞节 我们都是
Every Christmas was really about making
自己做礼物给对方的
presents for each other.
我们小时候总是搬家
We moved around quite a bit as kids.
我们住一起时 总是有这些
When we lived together it was always this thing,
莱托家的朋友、艺术家
总是有事做
there was always something going on,
我们在做艺术 做音乐
we were making art, making music.
周围总是有材料
There was always things around,
谁都可以随便捡起什么来 就地作画
anybody could pick up and draw or paint with,
或是穿上奇装异服 跳舞唱歌
and dress up and dance around and sing.
我是说 总有那种氛围
I mean there was always that energy,
那种创作的氛围
that creative energy.
他们从小就生活在音乐的环境里
They were indoctrinated into music quite really early.
到处是音乐 音乐 音乐 音乐
It was like music, music, music, music.
我妈妈以前总在车里唱歌
My mother used to sing in the car.
我记得她常常跟着歌曲哼唱
I remember she would harmonize with songs.
我记得那时觉得 她的声音好棒
I remember thinking that she always had a great voice.
她总是在听音乐
She was always listening to music
给我们听很多很棒的音乐
and exposed us to a lot of great music.
我从没真正想过
And I never really thought
自己有一天会成为做乐队的音乐人
that you could be a musician in a band.
我从没想过要出名
I never thought about fame,
我从没想过那些东西
I never thought about any of that stuff.
我们的童年 那段接触创作的经历
That early childhood, that creative exposure
真正塑造了我和我哥
really helped shape my brother and I
使我们受益匪浅
in an important way.
嗯 我喜欢 听起来很棒
Yeah, I like that, it sounds great.
我只是在想 桥段的部分我该怎么打？
这段确实是挺难
It's definitely a tough place
不容易打出花样来
to play something different I think.
这段是怎么唱的?
What do the vocals say?
马上 高潮那段?
Right away, when they go off?
等等 我都不知道和声是啥样的
Wait, I don't even know the chorus.
也别着急
It's also no rush.
咱们慢慢来就行
We should just take the time it needs
把它弄好了
to get it right.
如果咱们要做上三天
And if we have to do it over 3 days,
那就做三天
we'll do over 3 days.
我只是体会啊 我就... 你懂的
I'm just in it. I just... You know...
然后就 它就没了 哦老天 好吧
And then, it's gone... Oh my god, okay.
不 我知道了
No, I got that.
就是这样的 好了
That's the way it is, that's all.
咱们相互鼓励 做的时候也享受这一过程吧
Let's encourage each other to enjoy it as well.
发现之旅
This discovery.
因为东西很不错
Because it's awesome stuff,
你做的那个 小陷阱般的处理
the feel that you came out with the snare,
特别酷 你以前从没做过
totally cool and you never done it before.
回头庆祝吧
咱们做的时候也欢乐一点吧
Let have a bit of joy while we do it.
好得很  工序不同嘛亲~
That's all good... Different processes man.
我欢乐着呢
I am enjoying it.
我耍到他了
I got him all fooled.
完成！
我们进展不错 但还有好多东西要做
We getting there, but there's still lots to do.
我从没听过哪家唱片公司
I never heard of a label
是不坑艺人的
that doesn't screw an artist.
你找哪个艺人跟唱片公司审计一下
You talk to anybody who audits their label
他们(艺人)肯定是欠钱的
they're always own money.
没特殊情况的话
And if nothing else,
一般唱片公司都会攥着艺人的钱
usually the label holds back enough money
这样你审计的成本过高
that your cost of auditing is such
你就不会去审计了 所以..
that you won't do it, so...
商业模式就是这样 坑艺人来赚钱
That's the business model is screwing the artist.
财务上的条款一直就是模糊不清的
The financial practices have been shady
从一开始就是
since the beginning of time.
从爷爷辈的年代传下来 从五六十年代
It's been grandfathered in since the 50's and 60's
摇滚乐刚兴起时就是这样
when rock and roll really started.
从50年代 那时候他们就在坑艺人了
In the 50's, they were screwing the artist then,
但那时远远涉及不到这么多钱
but there was much much less money involved.
然后你进入60年代
Then as you start to go into the 60's
70年代 从热门专辑到垃圾专辑
and the 70's, the hit to shit ratio is
分账都是那么低 人们都说:
so bad that they're saying:
"嘿 咱不能给当红艺人们钱,"
"Hey! You know, we can't pay the hit artist
"因为还要靠他来养活那些 垃圾的艺人呢"
cause he is paying for all the bad artists."
这就要说到音乐产业的建立了
It goes back to how the music industry was set up
在录音行业的起步阶段
in the very early stages of the recording industry,
占那些没文化 好糊弄的艺人们的便宜
taking advantage of uneducated, easily swayed
他们也不太在乎钱
artists who don't really care about the money.
不幸的是 分道扬镳是常有的事
Unfortunately there's a lot of fall out with,
还是 乐队薪酬的事 你懂的
still with bands getting paid, you know.
我们得起诉唱片公司 才能拿到钱
We had to sue our label to get paid.
他们创造了这样一个奇怪的 错综复杂的系统
They've created this strange convoluted system
让你得变成个专业律师
that you have to be a lawyer
才能真正掌握... 或是数学家
to really understand... Or mathematician.
典型的唱片合约
A typical record deal is structured
结构是这样的:
something like this:
唱片公司付一笔预付款,
The record label gives an advance say:
比如25万美元吧 给艺人录专辑用
$250.000 to the artist to record an album.
艺人于是录了专辑
The artist then records the album.
假设这张专辑买了50万张
Suppose that the album sales 500.000 copies
每张10美元 收益是5百万美元
at $10 each yielding 5 Million Dollars.
唱片公司先把他们的分账
The record label then takes their cut out
从五百万里抽出 一般是总销售额的85%
of the 5 Million, typically 85% of the total sales.
给艺人们剩下75万美元
Leaving the artist with 750.000 dollars.
但是 在艺人收到钱之前
But before the artist receives any payments,
公司首先会减去预付款
the label first deducts the advance.
此外唱片公司还要扣掉其他费用
In addition the record label recoups other costs
例如: 录音费用
such as: recording costs,
一半的推广费用
half the promotion costs,
一半的MV费用 还有巡演资金
half the video costs, and tour support.
如此 艺人们还倒欠唱片公司
This leaves the artist 425.000 Dollars
42.5万美元
in debt to the record label.
这项债务流转到
And then this debt gets carried on
下张专辑
to the next album,
下下张专辑
the next album,
再下一张专辑
and the next album.
我不知道大家有没有看到过
I don't know if most people have seen
长期合同 那可真是疯狂
long form contracts, they're insane.
有那么多的细节 那些细枝末节的东西全都含在里面
And there's all these little, these little things throwin' in.
跟立法差不多
It's kind of like legislating,
你懂的 跟为政府制定法律一样
you know, legislature for a government.
他们写上这一大条 但在这条之下
They put up this big issue
but underneath that issue
又有比如17条其他的细则
there's like seventeen other little laws
他们会写进去 但不会告诉你
that they threw in, that they are not talking about.
所以 当你同意这一项条款的时候
So, when you say yes to this one thing
你其实是在同意
you are actually saying yes
比如说 45条其他条款
to like forty-five other things.
有一条更差的
There's a worse one,
他们以前还收取网络下载的 损耗费用
they use to have damage fees with digital downloads.
网络下载?
Digital downloads?
他们好像 一开始他们就像是
Like, at first they were doing that like
犯了谋杀 还想侥幸逃脱一样
they just trying to get away with murder, you know.
像是 "就这么写上吧,"
It just like "let's leave in there,
"看他律师能不能看出来" 这样的
let's see if the lawyer sees it" kind of thing.
合同里的其它的隐藏条款
Some other hidden items that the contract
还包括: 包装费
includes are: packaging costs,
他们会在艺人分账里 扣掉上限25%的
they deduct up to 25% of the artist cut
名为 为塑料盒和封面图片
known as the royalty to cover the expense
所支付的版税
of plastic cases and artwork.
这项费用甚至在数字下载中也包括
This cost is even administered to digital downloads
而下载的版本是不存在盒子和封面的
where packaging is non-existent.
还要扣除10%的运输损耗
10% is deducted to cover breakage costs during shipping.
从黑胶唱片的时代就有这些费用
They started in the vinyl era,
到后来CD光盘取代了黑胶唱片
continued when CDs replaced vinyl
如今到了数码下载的年代 这项费用依然存在
and still applies today with digital downloads.
减除10%的赠送费用 也是一项陈旧环节
The 10% free goods deduction is an antiquated
经销商购买100张唱片
system where retailers purchased 100 albums
就会另外得到10张免费赠送的
but are given an additional 10 albums at no charge.
而艺人的薪酬只按销售出的唱片来算
Since the artist is only paid on album sold.
他们不会因这些赠品得到补偿
they are not compensated for those free albums.
这项扣费 也同样用于
This deduction still continues
网络下载为主的市场
even in a digitally dominated market.
艺人们为这么多人 挣来这么多钱
Artists generate so much money for so many people
这些人很多都
that have nothing to do with
与创作过程毫无关联
the creative process at all.
你想找一条艺人不被剥削的路
There is no road you can go down
是找不到的
that the artist isn't fucked.
大多数有工作的人们
Most people out there who have jobs,
都可以去找自己的老板要求加薪
they can go to their boss ask for a raise,
他们要是实在不满意
they can leave and go get another job
也可以离开 跳槽
if they are not happy.
而作为音乐人就不能那样
Musicians don't really have that ability to do that.
顺便说一句 "如果我们(唱片公司)不喜欢,
And by the way, if we don't like,
"如果我们不想再推你的专辑了,
if we don't feel like pushing your records anymore
"我们觉得你不会大卖,
we don't fell you gonna sell,
"那我们也不会放你们走,
we're not gonna let you go,
"我们只会把你放到一边,
we're just gonna put you on the shelf over here,
"我们不会真正让你做音乐,
we won't really let you work
"但也不会让你离开我们公司"
but we're not gonna let you leave either.
就像是一桩毫无意义的婚姻
It's like being in a bad marriage.
你想 要是你丈夫老是打你,
At what point does your husband beat you up
或是你妻子总打你 你会说:
or your wife beat you up and you say:
"我受够了 我要走了"
I had enough I'm leaving.
现在就是这么个情况
That's the point we are at right now.
我等会儿回来 Irving的电话
I'll be back in a second, Irving is calling.
他跟我说 "这个30秒上火星的事 咱怎么做呢..."
"因为我们肯定要告到最后的"
然后我说  好 我给你解释一下你为什么不能
其他唱片公司会给你们很大压力
相信我 你是新手 我可不是
你要上庭 就得当着加州陪审团的面
与一个签了九年合约 却没拿到一分钱的乐队对质
你们会败诉  到那时候...
业内各家唱片公司会做出无数动作
你们会被业内所有人孤立
我说 你看 现实是这样的...
你们花八十亿美元买这个公司
在你们名下 除了酷玩乐队
他们是唯一名副其实的世界级乐队了
不发这张专辑 你们承受不起的
别犯傻了
你得回去找Guy Hands.  然后他说
"那我做不到."  我说 噢那你跟我说...
“当事人先生做不到”
那很好啊 没关系啊
我说 那你就等着吧 这张专辑很快就会出
知道吗 然后他就说 “我们不会调解的”
诉讼已经为我们带来很多负面影响了 媒体压力很大
我说 不不不  我们还没开始宣传这官司呢
我们公司内外 有着亿万个艺人
只有两个乐队与唱片公司有法律纠纷
碎南瓜 和三十秒上火星...
都是跟EMI
他们能阻止我们发布专辑吗?
Can they stop us from putting a record out?
要改变，就要建立新体系，使旧体系失效。
——理查德·巴克明斯特·富勒
(著名建筑设计师)
真酷啊
It's really cool.
这是日本太鼓
This is Taiko drumming
我在学习打太鼓
and I'm learning about Taiko drumming.
Shannon演奏起来像个野兽
Shannon is a beast of a player.
他不是演奏歌曲
He doesn't play in a song,
而是融入其中
he takes the song over.
他栖息于之 活在其中
He inhabits it, he lives it,
与之同呼吸
he breathes it.
他打鼓时散发着一种能量
There's an energy that he has when he drums
非常震撼 他充满着野性气息
that's fantastic. He's very animalistic.
他完全是在情感上共鸣
He's completely emotionally reacting.
看他表演
It's absolutely fascinating
真是一种视听盛宴
to watch somebody like that.
我哥哥一向热爱音乐
My brother always had a love of music.
他真的充满了热情
He had a real passion for it.
要不是他 我肯定不会做这个
I would certainly not be doing this if it wasn't for him.
我人生中唯一重视过的 就是音乐
The only thing I took seriously in my life was music.
在三十秒上火星之前
Before Thirty Seconds to Mars
我不知道自己想做什么
I wasn't sure what I wanted to do.
我做过建筑工人 我做过...
I was doing construction, I was...
违法的事
Breaking the law.
Jared常常取笑那些误入歧途的孩子
Jared often jokes about kids from the wrong side of the tracks,
我绝对就是那种孩子
I was definitely one of those kids.
他会消失 你知道
He would disappear, you know,
他会突然人间蒸发
he would just disappear.
我从来不知道他在干什么
I never knew what he was doing.
后来我就遇到了人生的瓶颈
I reached a point in my life where
我需要某种改变
I needed some sort of change and
而对当时的我来说 音乐是唯一靠谱的
music was the only thing that made sense.
他和Jared开始经常一起演出
He and Jared started playing together a lot.
那时我才重视起来
That's when it got serious.
那时我就: "噢! 好吧!
That's when I was like: "Oh! Okay!
"我要走这条路了"
I need to follow this path."
他才是对做音乐真正充满动力的
He was the one that was motivated to make music.
他对音乐才是 "要么做 要么死"的
He was the one that was do or die with it.
我们一起演奏时散发出的能量
Just the energy of us playing together.
真让人兴奋
That was exciting.
我只想演奏 演奏 演奏 演奏
I just wanted to play, play, play, play.
好了 秘密据点 拉钩保密?!
Okay. Secret spot. Pinky swear?
反正我也找不到 所以不用担心
I'll never be able to find it anyway. So, don't worry about it.
好 到底啥事?
So, what's the deal?
过两天你要去开个很久的会
You had a long meeting the other day.
嗯 EMI想要达成个协议
Yeah, EMI wants to make a deal.
有意思
Interesting.
虽然是个渣协议 但总是个协议
It's a shitty deal but, it's a deal.
那么 咱们有两种选择
So, we have a couple of options.
一种是激动人心的: 我们自立门户
There's the option that's exciting to go on our own.
感觉有了这样的独立精神,
It feels like there's a lot of opportunities
机会就会像潮水般涌来 只要有这种心态...
with that independent spirit and taking the mindset at...
不跟那个 不作为的公司签
Rather than signing an antiquated deal with a company
过时很久的老套合约
that has no interest in really doing anything
他们眼里只有钱
except making the numbers work.
但那是现实
But that's the reality,
如果你想签个唱片合同
if you want to sign a record deal.
你就得那样
That's what you're doing.
居高临下 两手准备
High nose. Both options.
Jared?
两手准备可都是要赌很大的
Both options are a big gamble.
嗯 我知道的不太多 所以没主意
Yeah, I don't know enough to have a real opinion.
但看起来 好像咱们自立门户
But it's seems like going on our own
是唯一的选择了
is the only way to go.
我不知道 这很难
I don't know, it's hard.
你给我说一个 不签任何唱片公司
Give me a name of one band
却取得了全球范围成功
that's had continued worldwide success
的乐队名字
without a label.
我说不出来
I can't give you one.
有人说 就签约吧
Some people say to take the deal.
完事
Settle.
嗯... 能签就签
Yeah... Just take whatever deal you can get
现在的形势这么混乱
cause this is so fucked right now.
基本上 你找唱片公司
Basically, you're looking for a record company
就是处理各种具体事务用的
to handle very specific things
比如推广 营销 以及其他的
like promotion, marketing, and things
我自己一点也不想做的事
that I don't really want to have to deal with.
对
Right.
如果咱们完全独立 我就得...
If we go completely independent, I'll end up...
把全部生活都投入进去  早晨 中午 晚上
That will be my life - morning, noon and night
都得用来做唱片公司做的 所有事
- is going to be having to have a record company.
你想玩"进击"吗
You feel you want to push army.
嗯 我想玩"进击"
Yeah, I want to push army.
你自己选一块石头
You take the rock of your choice,
或是别的大块东西 看你心里有多大的事了
or a bolder depending how big your issue is.
然后你把它扔过山崖
And you throw it over the precipice
扔的时候 你要大叫
and when you throw it, you scream,
释放出你生活中
and you let go of this particular aspect of
内心的特殊情绪 或是困扰你的事情
who you are or something in your life that's plaguing you.
然后你就把它抛之脑后 然后...
And you leave it behind and...
然后 嗯 这就是咱现在要做的
And, well, we gonna do it right now.
我先来还是你先来?
I'm gonna start or you wanna?
我先来吧
I go first.
嗯 你先
Yeah, you go first.
看你有多大能耐
Let's see what you got.
我听见有人叫 "哎呦!"
I just heard somebody say "ouch!"
不错诶
That's pretty good.
没有落地吗 发生了什么...
It never landed... what's that been...
真特么变态
This is so fucking nuts.
嗯
Yeah.
对了 我想出
By the way, I think I came up
新专辑的名字了
with a name for the album.
是什么?
What is it?
<全面开战>
"This is War."
现在做音乐 录歌 比以前容易多了
It's easier than ever to make music and record it.
拍MV并录制好
It's easier than ever to make videos
也容易的多
and record them properly.
把它们发布出来也很容易
It's easier than ever to put them out there
但是要使它们被听到 却是前所未有的难
but it's harder than ever to make them heard
得到点击量很难 因为网络上有太多声音
or have them heard because there's so much noise
所以唱片公司
on the internet so a record company
仍要承担起 帮助筛选这些
still has to do the job of helping to filter that
并加以适当宣传
and to promote things properly
让歌曲受到关注的工作
so that they can get noticed.
而且不用唱片公司 也能很成功的艺人
And there's certainly exceptions of artists
这样的例外显然也是有的
that have done well without a record company
但是大多数来讲 广大的艺人群体
but by in large the overwhelming majority of artists
那些功成名就 你懂的
that have achieved, you know,
取得了大范围成功的艺人 都是签了大厂牌的
major success, have been signed to major labels.
大厂牌 都是Cyclopes独眼巨人
Major labels are giant Cyclopes,
OK Go乐队主唱
他们有一只怪物般的能量强大的巨眼
and they have one very monstrously powerful eye
就在他们额头正中
right in the middle of their forehead
当它看向你时 你懂的
and when it's staring at you, you know,
全世界都明亮发光
the world is a very bright and shiny place.
而它不看你时 你就得不到任何关注
And when it's not, there is no getting attention of that thing.
如果我认识的某乐队要签个大厂牌
If I knew a band was going to sign a major label deal,
我一定会尽力劝阻他们
I would probably try to dissuade them
或者至少也要问清
or I would at least try to figure out
他们以为自己能从中得到什么
what they thought they were gonna get out of it.
如今唱片公司越来越少地
Increasingly, artist development is a term
使用"艺人发展"这个词了 你懂的
that's not even used at record companies, you know.
他们偶尔也提"艺人发展"
They use the word artist development
但这一般是个禁忌话题
but it's offensive to a certain point
因为他们才不管什么"艺人发展"
cause they don't really do that.
他们找数据
They look at the profiles,
过去是在MySpace上找
in the old days, it was MySpace,
现在是在Facebook, YouTube, Twitter上
the profile numbers now it's Facebook,
找数据资料
YouTube, Twitter.
不用唱片公司 你能独立卖掉1万 2万张专辑吗
Can you sell 10 / 20 000 on your own without a label
如果能 他们就该关注你了
and if so, then they start paying attention,
你懂的 只是比较关注 嗯
you know, kind of thing, but yeah,
但也不是关注艺人的发展
but it's not artist development.
那签的都是自己已经颇有成就的艺人
That's already signing an artist that's developed itself.
我想现在人们签约唱片公司 真正原因是
I think the main reason people really want labels now
正规性 尤其当你是个新人乐队
it's legitimacy, especially when you are a new band that,
你所作的选择真的事关重大
that what you're doing really kind of matters
受到媒体的曝光 真的很重要
and is part of something, and to get the press,
让人们逐渐认同你
to get people believing in you.
所以显然 当乐队自身影响变大之后
So obviously, bands when they get big on their own
他们签唱片公司就是为了: 正规性
then they sign with a label for that: Legitimacy.
Topspin传媒公司 首席执行官
我们学到的一点就是
One thing we've definitely learn
艺人们需要协助
is that artists need help.
摇滚乐队宣布独立
公制乐队就是个好例子
Metric is a great example.
他们是第一个 进入电台流行榜单前五位的
They were the first artists to break top 5
独立艺人团体
in pop radio with no label.
但如果你跟他们的经理人Matt Drouin聊
But if you talked to Matt Drouin
他就会告诉你:
who manages Metric, he will tell you:
"我们雇来制作专辑的人
"We had more people working on that record
"比在唱片公司时还要多
than if we were at a label.
"我们只是自己雇他们而已 所以 没错
We just hired them ourselves so, no,
"我们是没有签厂牌
we didn't have a label but
"我们差不多是自己建立了整套的员工系统"
we kind of built our own staff around it."
阿曼达·帕尔默对RoadRunner唱片公司说：
请甩我
我离开唱片公司时 基本就知道
When I got off the label, I pretty much knew
我不想再签一家
I didn't want to sign with another one.
我知道 没有什么比自己直接与我的粉丝交易更好的了
And I knew nothing could beat doing direct business
音乐人
并不是...
with my fans, it wasn't...
世界上任何合约也比不上这样
There was no deal in the world that was that good.
我都数不清自己收到了多少邮件
I cannot tell you how many eMails
粉丝们纷纷跟我说:
I've got from fans saying:
"我们想直接支持你,
"We want to directly support you.
"我们该怎么做 才能不让钱跑到唱片公司手上?"
How can we do it so your label doesn't get the money?"
阿曼达·帕尔默谈论
其百万美元启动项目
“音乐的未来”
你给人们提供超赞的音乐
Give people awesome music
他们就会很乐意帮助你
and then make it very easy for them to help you.
而且他们真的会
And they will.
我之前说过 有好多艺人
There are lots of artists, like I said
Chester French乐队主唱
"声破天"音乐软件驻唱艺人
都面临着这个这个选择
who were finding themselves with this choice
并不是说
and it is not to say
唱片公司不会赢得诉讼
that the labels can't win the argument
而是说艺人该如何利用唱片公司
as to why an artist should use them
与他们合作 呃... 不过确实
and partner with them. Em... But it is to say
还有很多种途径可以选择
that there is a great number of tools available
让独立艺人们可以自行制作
to independent artists to do it on their own
这样做出来 也不一定会
and they are not necessarily considerably
比唱片公司做的差
inferior to the label choice.
节拍数是多少?
What's the BPM?
开!
GO!
下一段副歌
Next chorus!
感谢大家 祝您丫的今日愉快!
Thank you very much, have a nice fucking day!
我那时21岁 只要能以音乐为生
I was 21 years old and I would do anything
让我干什么都行
in order to be able to play music for a living.
但我已经下定决心要放弃了
But I had made the choice to give up.
我意识到已经错过了机会
I realized I had missed my boat.
我已经计划好 要卖掉我所有的设备
I had made plans to sell all of my gear,
我不想 留下任何关于音乐生涯的记忆
I didn't want to have any like, memory of the music life.
第二天 大概是在我下定决心后
The next day, after like, making this choice,
我就接到了电话
is when I got the call to see if
问我想不想来面试
I was interested in auditioning
加入三十秒上火星
for Thirty Seconds to Mars.
我那时几乎完全破产 一点钱没有
I'm like completely broke. I have no money,
什么都没有 我只有一把吉他
I have nothing at all. I have a guitar
还有点破设备 我求着我爸妈
and some crappy gear. And I begged my parents,
我说 就是这次了 我能感觉到
I was like, this is the one, I can feel it.
我知道 我能拿到它
I know, I'm gonna get this.
不论怎样 什么都不能阻止我入选
No matter what, nothing gonna stop me from getting this,
如果我没通过 我会死的
I will die if I don't get this.
我们当时面试了大概有几百人
We're auditioning like hundreds of people.
他走进来就说:
He walks in and he says:
"我来就是告诉你们,
"I just want to let you guys know
"你们不用再找别人了..."
you don't have to look any further..."
我当时那么狂妄 那么蠢
I was so cocky and so stupid.
我表现成那样 完全有可能把一切都搞砸
It could have gone so badly, the way I was acting.
我就说：好啊 嗯 那咱看看吧
I was like, alright, well, see what you got.
他们把机会给了我
They took a chance on me.
我不是长得最漂亮的孩子
I wasn't the coolest looking kid.
我肯定也不是那里最棒的吉他手
I certainly wasn't the best guitarist out there
但显然我身上有某种东西 被他们看中了
but there was obviously something that they saw in me.
诉讼第75天
与EMI重订合约 摆脱二百万美元的债务
Re-signing with EMI, gets rid of 2 Million Dollars of all debt
也摆脱3000万美元的官司
and gets rid of the Thirty Million Dollars lawsuit
但那真他妈气人啊 这样解决   -我知道
but that fucking pissing me, this won,    -I know
这甚至不是打架的那种
and it's not even the fight
可以打倒某人的斗争
to fight to beat somebody.
这场斗争是为了 为了正义 为了公平!
It's the fight to... to... for what's right, what's fair!
你妥协一些 签下合约
You sign a deal in a way to compromise
但你这样做是为了
but you're doing it so that
可以打入内部
you could get in on the inside,
与对方合作
work with somebody
然后改变现有模式的基础
and change the fundamentals
而不是用对抗的方式解决
that way rather than a confrontation.
是啊 从内部改变它
Yeah, changing from the inside out.
没错
Exactly.
或是 可不可以从外部对抗它?
Or do you confront it from the outside?
我们再也不会有这样的机会了
We would never have this opportunity again
用7年条款来打官司
to fight over the 7-year clause
然后努力做到 改变一点(这个体系)
and to go and like, change a part of...
完全如此
Absolutely.
不仅是改变音乐行业
Not just the music business
还有我们的合约的签订方式
but you know, the way that our contracts are handled.
所以有一种... 你懂的
So there is this kind of... You know...
...道德讨伐
... Moral crusade.
对 是有点道德讨伐的意思
Yeah, there's a bit of a moral crusade.
如果他们把我们想要的一切
If they give us every single fucking thing
都他妈给我们
that we wanted
他们还是赚着大头啊
they would still be winning
而且他们也知道
and they know it!
重点就是这个 他们他妈的知道!
That's the thing they're fuckin' know it!
而且 妈的 他们在乎个屁
And by the way, what the Fuck! What do they give a shit,
每天下班 他们总能回到家 拿着工资
they gonna go home and get their salary at the end of the night.
他们要什么有什么
They're getting everything that they want.
他们有对艺人的完全控制权
Complete domination over the artist.
你要小心点 迷恋...
Just be careful you know, addict...
说迷恋可能太重了... 身在这个位置
Addicted is a strong word, to be the person
就总要面对斗争的
that is always gonna be in battle.
可能 现在并不是斗争的最佳时机
Maybe this is not the right time to fight this
不要抗争这个体制 先等待一阵
through this mechanism. Just bide your time.
用另一种方式来抗争 可能更好
It might well be a different way to fight it.
那样你就不用牺牲那么大
But you don't have to sacrifice as much.
唱片公司 总是比艺人更持久
The Company can always outlast the act.
这一点我们是从乔治·迈克尔的案子学到的
We learn this lesson primarily with Georges Michael.
他因为状告索尼 结束了他的职业生涯 是吧
He killed his career suing Sony, okay.
所以艺人总是先提出调解
So, the act has an incentive to settle
因为艺人们可不像IBM的工程师
because acts are not like engineers at IBM
可以工作上40年
who might work for 40 years.
披头士乐队状告EMI 要求赔偿数百万
金属乐队状告唱片公司 援引"7年"合同条例
Prince退出录音 转向其他行业
当年Prince被华纳公司气坏了
Prince was pissed off at Warner Brothers
于是停止了录音 就是那时
and stopped recording that's when
(注：1993年 华纳兄弟公司旗下艺人Prince将名字改成了
无法发音的"O(+>", 直到2000年与华纳解约后才改回来)
他把名字改成了那个符号
he changed his name to that symbol.
那是对华纳兄弟的反抗
It was a protest against Warner Brothers.
那怎么做才是正确的呢?
So, was that the right thing?
你知道 像他那样高度的人 去坐冷板凳
You know, at the kind of his height, to go sit on the sidelines
然后过了很多很多年之后才重新回来做音乐
and then go make music how many every years later
到那时谁还想为这个打官司?
when people don't want to fight about it anymore?
我不知道 谁输谁赢?
I don't know. Who won? Who lost?
林肯公园乐队想要解约
我只记到那时一直想:
I just remember the whole time thinking:
跟唱片公司相互斗气
It's not a good idea to go into a pissing contest
可不是什么好主意
with the record company,
他们有 他们拿着所有的牌
who has, who holds all the cards.
这就是场消耗战
It's like a war of attrition.
像是 谁先把对方耗垮了
It's like, whoever wears the other person down first
谁就赢
is going to win.
大西洋唱片状告Stone Temple Pilots乐队
的Weiland(主唱)和Kretz(鼓手)
碎南瓜乐队状告维珍唱片
平克·弗洛伊德乐队
因版税问题状告EMI
一般 唱片公司想给艺人们点教训
Usually the company they want to teach the act a lesson,
但是也需要艺人给他们挣钱
but they also need the revenue.
所以 假设艺人愿意在冷板凳上
So, assuming the act is willing to sit
坐上个一两年
on the sidelines for a year or two,
他们最后绝对能签个好点的合约
they can ultimately make a better deal.
只是但愿他们不会在这期间失去势头
Hopefully they've not lost momentum in the process.
OK Go乐队与EMI分手
你觉得EMI 作为大公司
Do you think as a corporation EMI
有没有骗过你?
ever lied to you?
OK Go乐队主唱
呃...我觉得EMI有没有骗过我们?
Erm... Do I think EMI ever lied to us?
我...
I am...
我在想怎么说才不用赔3000万块钱
I'm seeking not to get sued by 30 Million bucks,
好 我不告诉你他们是怎样的
So, I can't tell you or not how they are inside.
我是说 这是我们和解的唯一条件
I mean that's the only condition of
就是我要乖乖听话
our release that I got to be a good boy.
那 给我点专业意见吧 朋友
So, give me some counsel here, my friend.
我要做什么?
What am I doing?
咱先说明白 他们是一帮让律师洗了脑的白痴
他们认为自己被逼上了绝路 打碎了牙往肚子里咽
乐队律师
他们现在的三观就是这样的 不管是对是错吧
所以每次我跟他们说点什么 都像是在他们肚子里又深入了一厘米
他们就是这样看待世界的
-JL: 上帝啊
Jesus Christ!
还有再说一次 我不是说同意或赞成他们
只是把情况告诉你 知己知彼是很重要的
这样你就能对付他们了    -你丫应该去当诗人啊
...越来越厉害了
... It's getting worse.
我想我刚被你传上了感冒!
I think I just caught your cold!
好 你是音乐业老鸟了
Okay, what's your advice here
你的建议是什么?
as an expert in the music industry?
对我来说... 对我来说 我觉得...
To me... To me... I think that...
考虑到
I'm taking into account
你们说的情况
what you guys are saying,
我认为选择EMI比较靠谱
I think EMI is the safe bet.
因为 我之前也说过
Because, like I told you before,
我觉得 你们再为他们做一张专辑
I think you're doing one album for them
然后你们就两清了
and you'll be done with them.
所以 反正我会选更安全的这种
So, that's what I would do it's safer,
另一种(独立)就有点风险了
the other thing is riskier.
如果你们愿意冒险的话
If you want to take a risk.
明白
Got it.
不 重点是你们怎么想
No, it's how you feel, how you
你和Shannon还有Tomo怎么想
and Shannon and Tomo feel about it.
好 再见
Okay bye.
谢了 ... 哎--
Thanks. Hey!...
我想问他这次花了我多少话费
I wanted to ask how much that phone call costs me.
(下雪吧 下雪吧 下雪吧~)
(Let it snow, let it snow, let it snow)
--Dean Martin
太搞笑了 外面这么大的太阳
It seems funny getting a Christmas tree
却要来买圣诞树
when it's totally sunny outside
那哥们还穿着T恤呢
and the guy is in a tee-shirt.
嘿 这些全是特价的 她说
Hey! These are all the thrifty, she says,
这些都是 怪咖树
these are the Charlie Browns.
都有点 你懂的 树枝折了什么的
The ones that have like, you know, broken branches.
喂!
Yo!
来了
Yeah.
我觉得这棵太特么搞笑了吧
I think this one is pretty fucking funny.
烂成这样 他们怎么还卖...
This is all fucked up man, there is no way they even...
这儿居然写着99块 20块钱我都不要
It says 99 bucks, I ain't paying 20 bucks for that.
20块 他有... 瞧啊
20 bucks. He's got, look,
这里 这个枝节有关节炎
arthritis on the knuckle right here.
头发都要掉光了
His hair are falling out.
额滴神 风湿病啊
OMG. Rheumatoid.
他有着矮个子的一切悲哀
He's got short man's complex.
你要付我们多少钱把它拖走?
How much you gonna pay us to drag this out of here?
我说 你看看这玩意!
I mean look at this thing.
我知道 这太不好了
I know, it's so sad.
要我说 这是我这辈子
I mean this is the ugliest tree
见过的最丑的树了
I have ever seen in my entire life.
你要多少?
How much you think?
19.99
19?
好吧 我们要了
All right, we'll take it...
你想把这熊孩子放哪儿?
Where do you want to put this bad boy?
角落?
In the corner?
买的真值
That was a bargain.
她很高 很黑 很帅
She was tall, dark, handsome.
听好了...
Listen...
她很高...
She was tall...
好了... 她很高 很黑 很帅
Okay... She was tall, dark, handsome...
这烟让我入戏了 根本停不下来
The cigarette gets me in character. I can't help it.
她很高 很黑 很帅
She was tall, dark, handsome,
JJ像角马的一样大
hung like a wildebeest...
噢...咱要赔人家3000万啊
Ohhh... We've been sued for 30 Million bucks.
啊 咱真是...
Ahhh... We really are...
咱真是
We really are.
他们要是说: "去你妈的 啥也别说了,
What if they just said: "Fuck you! This is done,
"咱法庭见吧" 咋办
We're taking you to court."
她很高 很黑 很帅
She was tall, dark, handsome,
JJ像角马的一样大... 但我爱她!
hung like a wildebeest but I loved her.
Guy 你要怎样重组呢? 告诉我们吧
How you're gonna restructure Guy, just tell us?
Guy 为什么要裁掉那么多人呢?
Why are the job cuts necessary Guy?
Guy 你对你的员工有什么话想说吗?
What's your message to staff Guy?
EMI新闻集团的董事长葛涵思的口风很紧
EMI news's owner Guy Hands was tight lipped
在他到达剧院的路上
as he arrived at the cinema
去介绍该音乐股份公司的新走向
to outline the music group's new direction.
其员工得到内部消息
Inside staff learned that EMI is set
EMI打算裁员2000人
to axe up to 2000 jobs.
他们把公司翻了个底朝天
They stripped mine the place.
他们炒掉了一大堆人
They fired tons and tons of people.
百代EMI集团据悉将大幅裁员
他们让一些对唱片界 或音乐界
They put people in charge that never had any experience
一无所知的人来管理
in the record business or the music business.
他们开始把公司分散开来
They started to decentralize it.
建立了这些奇怪的单元制
They had all this strange pods
打破了原先比较传统的结构
instead of a more traditional structure.
他们还把重要的权力职位
They also put some people in positions of power
给了一些我认为完全不靠谱的人
who didn't make any sense to me whatsoever.
我一直旁观着
I see it all the time.
就是这些要大力改革的人
It is just the heavy hand of guys,
他们不懂这个产业
who don't understand the business,
却努力要告诉那些懂行的人
who try to tell people who do understand the business
应该怎么做
how to do their jobs.
我见过他一面 他跟我说:
I met with him once and he said to me:
"你们这些做音乐业的人,
"All you people from the music business.
"你知道 你们根本就不会做生意"
You know you really don't know how to run a business."
他们在公司的全球各区的领导部门
They installed a lot of people
酷玩乐队、披头士乐队
失去领导
安排了大批人手
across the global leadership of the company.
大部分人都安排在管理层
And most people see at management levels.
Guy Hands和泰丰资本的人员，...不信任唱片公司的总裁们
而原有的正经做唱片公司的主管
And these serious record company executives
在几个月内就全消失了
were gone instead in a matter of month.
显然 我有些成见
Obviously, I have a certain bias
前EMI旗下  Capitol音乐集团董事长
而且我在那儿 就要说出来
and I was there and I was very vocal
说出我的异议
about any of my disagreements.
进入EMI约3年后
Lee Trink离开了EMI
他们想重新建立公司架构
They wanted to restructure the company
而根据我的合同条款
and in the terms of my contract,
前EMI旗下  Capitol音乐集团首席执行官
没我的允许 他们不能这样
they couldn't without asking me
于是 他们还是做了
and so, they did it anyway.
进入EMI约3年后
Jason Flom离开了EMI
过去 当你说到EMI
In the old days, you say what is EMI thinking,
你能说上10个在那儿工作的人
you would name 10 people that have worked there
都是干了二三十年的
for 20 years or 30 years.
你会关心他们的想法
You'd worry about what they thought
但现在没有二三十年的老员工了
but there's nobody that's worked there for 20 years or 30 years.
再也不是当初那个公司 和那批人了
It's not the company or the people it ever was.
我们经历过EMI公司的很多次重组
We have been through so many regimes at EMI
从我们98年跟维京唱片签约到现在
since we signed a contract with Virgin Records.
我都数不清有过多少次
I can't even tell you how many it has been.
大概有8到12次
It is safe to say it is over eight less than twelve.
我看现在的员工没有一个
I don't think there is a single employee
是我们签约时就在那儿的
that was there when we signed our record deal.
我们要负担诉讼费
We would take care of the lawsuit.
光那就花光了我的钱
That's already cost me more money than I have,
我们乐队的钱
than we have as a band.
我们已经欠银行钱了
We've spent more money that we have in the bank.
对
Right!
不 我明白
No, I understand
我得去告诉他们:
I'm gonna have to tell them:
他们可以他妈的 跪舔我的丁日了
they can suck my fucking proverbial dick!
所以 可以说 EMI已经让我们破产了
So, in a sense, EMI has already bankrupted us.
Kempler(维珍唱片首席财务官)真是在管这个?
Kempler really is controlling this?
不 是财务部门在管这个
No, the money guys are controlling it.
你知道泰丰资本...
You know Terra Firma...
哦操他们大爷! 真他妈扯蛋
Well fuck them! That's such bullshit!
他们这些他妈的****
How could that motherfucking *beep* *beep*
怎么能坐那儿告诉我们
can sit there and tell us
他本来要做什么
that he was gonna do something
但又不做了?
and then not do it?
大洋彼岸 是Guy Hands
Across the pond, it's Guy Hands,
而在咱美国 是Jeff Kempler(美国维珍唱片首席财务官)
and here in America, it's Jeff Kempler.
我认为他可能是在朝Guy Hands炫耀
And I think that he is either trying to show off for Guy Hands
他认为他能扼制这一切
and he thinks that he's gonna strangle all this.
但我们有别的选择
We have other options.
我 我自己是要奉陪到底的
I, myself I'm ready to go all the way.
他们一副准备好的样子 很乐意
They're acting like they're so ready and happy
并且愿意与我们当庭对峙
and willing to just go into litigation
这样我就必须得准备作战方案了
that I'm having to prepare the battle plan.
我想这个合约涉及的所有人 都逐渐迷失了
I think everyone is getting lost in the deal
看不到这样对他们
and not seeing what a benefit
对我 能有什么好处
it probably could be to me and to them,
对我们来说 是想达成一项公平合理的协议
for us to work out something fair and reasonable.
但我不能 我就是不能啊
But I can't do, I just can't do it
要是不公平
if it's not fair.
我不能一边同意 一边感到自己吃了亏
I can't do it and feel I've been taking advantage of.
好了 那下一步是什么
Okay, so what's the next move here?
怎么?
What's up?
再过来一下   -好的
We need you again... (Okay)
我以为那首歌会挺容易的
I thought that was gonna be an easy song.
-嗯  -我不觉得
(yeah) I actually didn't think
这首歌简单
it was gonna be an easy song,
我就知道这首得特么蛋疼死
I knew it's gonna be a pain in the fucking ass!
呃 咱们能不能试试... 呃 你懂的
Em. Can we try... Em. Just... You know?
当然... 就是... 快一点
Sure... It's huh... Pretty fast.
一拍好 还是两拍好?
Is it better one foot or two?
一拍吧
One, I think.
真奇怪 这么快
It's so weird, it's so fast.
真麻烦
It's very awkward.
上帝啊
Jesus Christ!
你到底想要什么 哥们
You know what you want, man!
我要力量 力量
I need power... Need power...
一拍不够
It's not enough at one.
我会了兄弟 我亲弟弟 对吧?
I got it brother, my brother. Right?
一会儿再弄
We will work with this.
过一会儿叫你
We'll call you in a minute.
我不知道
I don't know.
完全迷茫
I have no idea.
速度上太不连续了
节奏上时快时慢
是 我也是人 我知道
所以我想让你...
这样就更流畅起来了
我是说 实际上...
你都还没练呢    -对
你要是练上个几天 我肯定你就能行了
好吧
我们可能得先做下一首歌了
留时间给你每天练一练这个
然后过个两三周我们再回来做这首
因为现在真是太不流畅
我已经做到最好了 哥们
那就想个更好的鼓点啊 我们必须要录这首歌
就这个鼓点了
要么咱干脆抛弃这首歌 要么咱就尽量...
就这个鼓点 哥们
你想要我怎样？
现在这样我没法唱
你给我再多的钱
我也没法正确地唱出来
这样不行
你能打开喇叭放一下吗？
你看这样一点怎么样:
What about a little bit of like:
有时候你觉得充满力量
Some days you feel so strong
然后 其他时候 你就觉得:
and then, other days, you're like:
我他妈在干嘛啊
what the fuck am I doing?
我想 我是不是正在毁掉一切?
I'm wondering if I'm ruining it?
我是不是正在毁掉Shannon和Tomo?
Am I fucking it all up for Shannon and Tomo?
有时候我感到好自信 好强势
Some days, I feel so confident, so strong,
就像: 没关系的
I'm like: it doesn't matter
这张专辑肯定会特别的好
this album is gonna be so good,
歌曲肯定超级棒
the songs are gonna be so great.
不用在乎我们属于哪家唱片公司
It doesn't matter what label we are,
人们一定会来听我们的歌 我们只是需要协助
we're gonna reach people but you need the help.
你需要... 你不可能所有的事都自己做
You need... You can't do it on your own.
而别的时候 我就在想:
And the other days, you just feel like:
我们他妈的是在干嘛啊?
what the fuck are we doing?
我也不知道
And I don't know,
也许我就不该这么斗争
maybe I'm fucked up to keep fighting.
我只出过一张成功的专辑
I've had one successful record.
我就争得像...
And I'm fighting like,
我是他妈的滚石乐队一样
I am the Rolling fucking Stones.
可我算个屁啊?
I mean who the fuck am I?
真是他妈噩梦哥们
It's a fucking nightmare, man,
整个事都是个他妈的噩梦
this whole thing is a fucking nightmare.
我是说 这一切过一年后就有可能...
I mean, all of this could be a year from now,
我是说 到时回头一看 说: "哇 我搞砸了!"
I mean, looking back and say: "Wow, I fucked up!
"我没签唱片公司,
I didn't sign with the label,
"专辑才他妈卖了12张"
the record sold 12 fucking copies."
我把所有的一切都投入这里面
I put everything that I have into this.
我的全部身家 一切 我们都是
My entire life, everything. We all have.
诉讼第112天
你还是别走这些
You don't want to get through
所有的诉讼程序了
all this fucking legal thing.
你也赢不了什么
And you don't win anything.
如果这是彩虹尽头的
If it was like a pot of gold
一滩金矿 我就去了
at the end of that rainbow, I'll do it...
你的赢头就是: 你什么也不失去
The win is: you don't lose anything.
明白吧 那还是赢的!
Hey, that's your win!
你赢 就是 诉讼费用你来付
The win is that you get to pay the legal fees.
那就是你的赢头
That's what your win is.
赢就是这样...
That's the win...
看你们有点沮丧
You look to have some fun.
我跟Kempler半年没说话了(EMI/维京首席财务官)
I haven't talked to Kempler in 6 months.
咱给他打个电话 你们的官司...
Let's call him. Your lawsuit...
嘿Brenna! 给Jeff Kempler打电话
Hey! Brenna, call Jeff Kempler.
我可能不会太客气 说真的
I'm gonna have trouble being nice, seriously...
嘿 我在机场的洗手间呢
Hey guys, I'm in the bathroom at the airport,
所以这儿有点吵
so it's a little loud.
可能也有点冷吧
It's probably a little cold, too.
好冷啊 怎么能这么冷
你冻病了我才高兴呢
Any place where it's cold for you makes me happy
我是Irving
It's Irving.
噢哥们 我能让你开心 我真是受宠若惊
再让你高兴点: 我现在感觉可烦了呢
趁我手机还没被没收 我先说几句
我是说 你知道我们也在努力 是吧
我打了很多电话 尝试了很多方案
我们真的在努力 我们也很想跟你们...
回到谈判桌上来...
你听起来像个冠冕堂皇的混蛋
You sound like a corporate fucking dick,
咱们还是说合同吧
let's just talk about the deal.
事实就是 你懂的
The reality of fact is that: it's, you know,
很难说服这些人(30STM)
it's really hard to advise these guys
跟你们这个垃圾破公司
to do anything with that piece of shit of a company
达成什么协约 说对 说不 滚吧你
that you work for, and say yes, say no, go away man,
没什么话说  就滚吧
just go away, if you don't want to do this.
还有在他们从你们手底下
And before they fucking sell the company out
卖空这破公司之前 把专辑发了
from under you guys, put out the record.
好的
Okay.
不过还是旅途平安啊 再见
But fly safe anyway. Bye.
对了 还有些次要问题   -对
Right. By the way just side issue.   -Yes.
唱片公司怎么样了?
How is the record company?
咋了?
What?
我就想感觉好点
I just want to feel good.
整个的谈判 感觉都不好
This all negotiations, it doesn't feel good.
就不该感觉好
It's not supposed to feel good.
不
No.
整个这个事 面对 动荡的时间
This whole thing. You've got the unstable time.
还有 动荡的EMI
You've got the unstable EMI.
一切都像 脱缰的野马一样
You've got the unstable maverick way.
这事...充满了动荡
The thing... It's all unstable.
所以完全没有(确定下来的)感觉
So, there's no feeling that's gonna be attached,
像是"噢 好了..."
to like: "Oh! Yeah..."
然后还有新专辑要做
Then you've got the album we're doing
还有一切的这些事
and you've got everything, dude.
有点动荡 你懂的
It's a little unstable, you know.
站出来的经理们
Managers who are standing up
都表示他们十分忧虑
and say they are very very worried
EMI存在的动荡
about the instability at EMI.
知名艺人 如电台司令乐队
Major acts like Radiohead and
和保罗·麦卡特尼 都与该公司分道扬镳
Paul McCartney parted ways with the company.
我刚跟我的制作人说了,
And I just said to my producers,
我说我发这张专辑
I said I want to feel excited
我想感到点兴奋
by releasing this record.
麦卡特尼称其唱片公司“无聊”
太乱了
It's just a mess.
他们想操纵我们
They're trying to manipulate us
让我们恐惧
with a little bit of fear.
他们从我们眼皮底下撤掉合约
They're pulling deals out from under our feet,
他们在耍我们 在糊弄我们
they're fucking with us, they're toying,
他们在发邮件 发信
they're sending eMails, letters
完全与我们对立
just outright hostile.
据报道 EMI的动荡 令Coldplay
The shakeup at EMI reportedly has Coldplay
正重新考虑将来续约的事
rethinking a future deal with the label.
罗比·威廉姆斯的经理人声称:
Robbie Williams's manager has been quoted as saying:
"该明星现在不急于发放新专辑
"The star is in no rush to put out a new album
电台司令乐队退出
罗比·威廉姆斯罢工
-至今已裁员1000人
"因为对新的管理模式缺乏信心"
due to a lack of faith in the new management."
今天是Guy Hands向其债权人之一的
Today marks the deadline for Hands
花旗集团支付款项的最后期限
to meet a payment to Citigroup, one of its creditors,
不然他将失去对公司的掌控
or he'll lose control of the firm.
这些人都是 说一套做一套的人
These people that they say one thing and that they do another thing.
他们这样做生意 真是恶心
It's disgusting that they do business like this.
他们怪不得自己名声这么臭
They wonder why they have a bad fucking name.
因为他们对人就像屎一样
It's because they treat people like fucking shit.
妈的他们活该遭现在这个灾
They deserve the fucking disaster that they are in the middle of.
出去走走 不然我该砸东西了
Walking out before I break shit.
你懂的 这你得教教我了
You know you've got to guide me here,
我脑子里一团乱麻 不知道该怎么做
I'm heel over my head, I don't know what to do.
呃 我也不知道
Huh, I don't know either.
这个傻逼诉讼就这么占领了我们的生活
It's amazing how this fucked-up-lawsuit
真是没法想象
is taking over our lives.
我觉得我们应该签
I feel like fuck we should just take
那个要死的合约 不管是什么
the god damn deal, whatever it is
就他妈签了吧
just fucking take it,
万一出更坏的事呢?
what if everything got worse?
这一部分 真是专辑里我最
This part of the record is always really
最最最看中的
really really important for me.
好像那里的背景伴奏
It's like the backing tracks are there,
有强烈的个性
they've got a lot of strong personality.
不管那是好是坏
It doesn't matter whether it's good or bad.
可以快 可以慢
It could be fast, it could be slow,
但都有着某种精华在里面
but they've all got some sort of essence to them
使歌曲脱颖而出
that makes the songs stand out.
现在 它像是正在灌入
And now, it's like filling in,
正在给整个画面上色
it's coloring the picture.
我觉得就是那个部分
And I think that's the part
是你一直所欠缺的
that has been missing from you.
我得说一句 卧了个大槽!
I have to say: holy fuck!
我今天的感觉就是这样
That's how I feel today.
没有那种 完 全 碉 堡 的东西
You don't have like undeniable.
对 咱现在是没有 没错
No, we don't right now as we speak, No!
我再在这儿坐上一年
I'll sit here for another year,
不行的话 我把这货整个中国特色掉
I'll Chinese democracy this motherfucker
一点问题没有
if I have to. It doesn't matter.
我完全明白你的意思
I know exactly what you're talking about
这也是做专辑时的正常阶段
and this is quite usual at this stage of making a record.
现在这个时期令你怀疑一切
You're now in the place where you're doubting everything.
一切都走向了某种瓶颈 而且从根本上讲
Everything is sort of plateauing and fundamentally,
没有什么能挑动你们的神经的了
there is nothing that's getting your juices going.
而我的建议就是
And what I suggest is
咱们得从大局着眼
that we need to look at the whole thing,
因为--
because...
我们肯定还差一首歌
We're definitely missing a song
这个我能明确告诉你
I can tell you that right now.
我同意你说的
No, I agree with you.
所以 可以这样
So, it might be that
这个阶段完全可以:
that has to be a period of just like:
"好 我们确实缺这个"
okay, we are missing this,
"我们确实需要再做一首歌"
we do need to do another song
但也许它还没写出来
but maybe it hasn't been written.
但在你们把其他的歌
But without at least getting
弄好之前
some of these other songs into point
你们找不到你们缺失的东西
you're not going to know what you're missing.
我希望这是 你懂的
I hope that this is mid... You know,
是专辑的中年危机
the midlife crisis of the record,
但我不知道 我是说 我们得质疑所有成果
but I don't know, I mean, we have to question everything.
在我看来 我觉得这是个很好的学习过程
对我而言 我觉得这是个很好的学习过程
学习当你实际上只能自食其力的时候
该如何制作唱片
因为我们没有唱片公司 没有人来管理
只有我们四个人在房间里
制作一张三十秒上火星乐队的唱片
这是个很陌生的情况
目前也没有任何出路
诉讼第139天
12月31日
现在是早上 凌晨的早上
It's the morning, early early morning,
外面还黑着
it's still dark out and
我们决定离开洛杉矶
we have decided to get out of Los Angeles.
去佛罗里达州
And go to Florida.
我不能接受
I just couldn't face
大除夕的什么特么也不做
not doing something for fucking New Year's Eve.
我们这一年都特么在辛苦着
We've been going at it all fucking year.
我这周要跳舞
I want to dance this week.
你会看见我跳成傻子
You're gonna see a dancing fool.
赞
Ditto.
去之前我得先吃早饭
I need breakfast before I face this shit.
每个人都放假去了
Everybody took a break.
Shannon去了夏威夷
Shannon went to Hawaii,
Tomo去了密歇根州
Tomo went to Michigan.
我觉得 空气中弥漫着各种
I feel like, there's a lot up in the air
我还意外发现
and it was serendipitous
这个假期正好处于
that the holiday break came at the time
这个我们成败在此一举的节点
when there was this make-or-break kind of place
既是专辑的关键点
we happen to be in for the record,
我们也遇到了创意瓶颈
for the creative parts of the album,
也是官司的关键点
for the lawsuit.
好没？ 她觉得你是Jared Leto
Ready? She thinks you are Jared Leto.
她让我到这儿来
She told me to come here
问问你是不是Jared Leto?
and ask you if you're Jared Leto?
嗯......是啊
Mmmm. Yep.
你真是? 真心的?
You are? Serious?
是滴
Yep.
你耍我们的吧?
Are you just fucking with us?
没...你好吗
No... How you doing?
我就知道
I knew it.
你好吗
What's up?
你可想不到 "哦这是迈阿密
You don't think: oh, it's Miami,
"会有这么些人"
there's gonna be all these people
"在沙滩上围拍你"
taking pictures on the beach.
Michael Jackson!
于是 我们逃走了
So, we escaped
去了某个鳄鱼塘之类的地方...
and went to some alligator farm or something...
真是别有风味 在沼泽里开始新的一年
There's nothing like starting your new year in a swamp.
仅在一月就有60万人失业
600 000 jobs lost in January.
道指已经跌破2000点
The DOW is already down 2000 points.
洛杉矶
（注：美国著名建筑设计师）
这可是弗兰克·劳埃德·赖特设计的房子
This is the Frank Lloyd Wright house.
我觉得这是个咱们录音的好地方
I thought that would be a great place for us
肯定灵感爆棚
to record and would be really inspiring.
你知道吗 刺激的就是
You know what's exciting,
我们要把这座房子的灵魂录进专辑里
we're gonna have the spirit of this house inside the record.
这真是个活生生的艺术品啊
This is a living, breathing piece of art.
这儿可真棒
艺术 正是我们在作品中一向所追求的
Art, it's something we all aspire our work to be.
有的人可以想到什么就做什么
Some people can do whatever they think of.
音乐制作人
而他们所想到的十分特别
And what they think of is special
并能感染他人 这样的人就是艺术家
and moves other people. Those people are artists.
这是他们对于所爱事物的
It's their bare honest truth
演员
最真实的表达
about something that they love.
我认为这是一种
I think it's one of the avenues
深及内心 探寻自我的途径
to get to oneself to find out who we are.
经久不衰的艺术 是最难的艺术形式
Timeless art is the most difficult form of art.
我看到克莱斯勒大厦
I see it in the Chrysler building,
看到协和式超音速飞机
I see it in the Concorde.
听到甲壳虫乐队...(都是永恒的艺术品)
I hear it in the Beatles...
这个行业就是: 我恨这帮人
The business is, I hate all those people,
这帮人都是吸血蝙蝠
those people are leeches.
他们只关心自己的饭碗
All they ever do is care about not losing their job.
他们从不关心艺术的价值体现
They never once care about enhancing the value of art.
现今我们行业整体的一大弊病
One of the problems we have in business at large right now
就是商业集团在掌管这些生意
is corporations own these businesses.
所以 永远都很难改变
So, it's very difficult to change it ever
因为它必须靠着这个机制来运转
because it has to be this machine that keeps going.
另一方面的问题就是
The other part of the problem is that
行业本身把制作过程同化了
the business itself has homogenized the process.
唱片公司来告诉乐队写什么
The record company tells a band what to write,
如何写 跟谁合作写
how to write it, who to write with.
你知道 把哪首作为单曲
You know. What is gonna be a single,
哪首不作为单曲
what's not gonna be a single.
我认为这样对创意层面的管控太严重了
And I think has far too much control on a creative level.
这样 一切都逐渐变得十分雷同
So, that everything starts sounding very much the same.
这就像个钟摆一样
That's a pendulum. I think.
不可避免地,
What inevitably happens is
公司们总在与艺人抗衡
that companies that are wrestling with that
在创意, 感性  与融合科学之间
creative, intuitive, blended with science,
他们往理性的方向摆的太远
they swing way too far to the
"让我们遵从科技和数据测算"
lets-be-scientific-and-mathematical.
像是把西瓜和芝麻一起丢了
Sort of throw the baby out with the bath water
然后就失去了对灵感
and lose that comfort with intuition,
创意敏感
creative sensitivities
以及犯错误的信心
and mistakes get made that way.
唱片公司一直在巩固
The record companies keep consolidating
于是很多都优胜劣汰掉了
and so, there's less of them
当然这主要是因为
and that's dictated by the fact
这是一个行业 而随着行业萎缩
that it is a business and as business shrinks
越来越少的人购买音乐
and there is less people buying music.
唱片公司能怎么办?
What do the record companies do?
他们削减成本 于是结果就是
They cut cost. So, as a result of that
艺人们能去的地方就少了
you have less places for artists to go,
能签约的艺人更少了
less people getting signed.
我觉得永远不会停止...
I don't think it ever ends...
我觉得永远不会停止
I don't think it ever ends.
我做这一行19年了
I've been in this business 19 years
从我入行时就是
and it was going on, the day I started
到现在一直是 你懂的
and it's going on now, you know.
我不知道艺术和商业
I don't know that art and commerce
是否能美满地联姻
ever get married like that.
诉讼第143天
喂
Hello
Jared, Irving要跟你说话
Jared they're grabbing Irving
乐队经理人
没人告诉我们 他们要怎样
Nobody told us what they were gonna do.
他们不见我们
They wouldn't meet with us.
他们不喜欢我们!
They don't like us!
嗯 我现在也有点不太喜欢他们了呢
Yeah, I'm beginning not to like them very much either.
纪录片改变了你自己的音乐?
Documentary changes your own music?
嗯 我现在也不太明白
Yeah, I don't understand how
怎么就发生了
that even happened.
我都不知道我们为什么提这个
I don't even know why we brought this up.
早知道就不提纪录片的事了
We shouldn't have never even brought it up.
不 我是说 他们怎么也会反对
No, I mean he would have say "no" later,
你早晚也得提
you had to bring it up.
你不能就这样把音乐加进去...
You couldn't have just put the music in...
你得说... 明白我的意思吗?
You had to say... You know what I mean?
就是说 如果有一幕是
So, if there is a shot of me sitting
我在房子里 坐在钢琴前
and playing one of my songs
弹着我的一首歌
on the piano, at the house,
我还得征求EMI的允许
I'll have to get permission from EMI
才能发布这个纪录片?
in order to release this documentary?
没错 他们差不多就会那么说
Correct. They're  basically gonna say that
根据合同 咱们还要再做2张专辑
we have a contract ready for 2 more albums,
所以这是合同的规定
so this is a settlement of that contract
而根据那个旧合同
and under that old contract
你不能在DVD里放进任何不加他们版权的音乐
you couldn't put any music in the DVD without them,
拥有音乐的只是他们 不是你
they own the mere music, not you.
还有根据他们说的
And the way they've worded it,
他们是不是还有这纪录片的最终剪辑权?
did they have like final cut over this thing?
他们说: 我们要先看看样片
They're like: we need to see a copy of it
然后咱们再谈
and then we'll talk about it
看给不给你音乐的授权
if we're gonna license you the music for it,
是不是这个意思?
is that basically how it is?
嗯 他们是想让你放弃这片子
Yeah, they're trying to make you abandon the project.
想让我放弃这片子
Trying to get me abandon the film.
是的 那 我接个电话
Yep. So, let's have a call.
好
Okay.
拜
Bye.
全来了
It all comes down.
所以基本上 就是卖掉纪录片
So basically, you sell the film
来换唱片合约
for the record deal.
要不你就把EMI从片子里删掉
Or you just take EMI out of the film.
因为那样他们就会说:
Cause then they'll say:
"当然好啊 我们让你发"
"Sure, we'll let you put it out."
咋样啊妹子们? 喂?
What's up girls? Hello?
乐队律师
我看吧 公司里大概分了这么两派:
To me, there is quite two factions in this company.
一派不想跟你们签约
There's one that just doesn't want to make a deal with you
另一派想跟你们签约
and there's one that does want to make a deal with you.
乐队经理人
说你不能做纪录片,
It's a further slap in the face to say
相当于又是句打脸的话
you can't do the documentary.
它没有商业价值
It makes no rational financial sense.
我想我就回去找他们 说
I think I go back to them and say,
纪录片归我们所有
we own the documentary
我们想怎么拍就怎么拍
and we can do what we want with it.
你能不能再跟他们说一次 纪录片里的生机
Could you reiterate that there's more to life out there
都比这个摇摇欲坠的公司多得多?
than a bloated failing corporation?
啊 操... 今天真是 今天真是的
Aaahh Fuck... What a day. What-a-day!
还没更糟呢:
Could have been worse:
唱片公司完全可以跟我们说
the record company could have told us
操你们祖宗吧... 哦等等 他们就是这意思
to go fuck ourselves. Oh wait! They just did.
EMI应该觉得丢人
EMI should be ashamed of themselves.
他们今天给我们通知了
They came back with their offer today.
只要我们有新进展
As soon we're getting somewhere,
公司里的一些超级白痴大傻逼
some giant fucking moron at the company, thinks
认为他们就能来控制并拥有它
they're gonna control and own this.
但你猜怎么着? 他们可以来跪舔我!
But guess what? They can kiss my fucking ass!
到此为止了 我们不再合作了
It's over. We are not doing that.
我刚跟Irving谈了 那帮傻逼啊
Just talked to Irving. Fucking idiots, man.
好
Good.
黑心公司的傻逼自恋狂们
Greedy fucking corporate hubris.
我们提议开个会 是吧
We suggested a meeting, right?
这样我们就能面对面
So, we can all sit face to face
不至于为这事迷失了
and not get lost in the deal
可以人性地处理问题
and to be human about things.
但他们说不 我就告你一声
They said no. Just so you know.
他们说不 他们以为
They said no, they think
他们可以跟我共同拥有那段音乐
they're gonna own that piece of music with me
我只能在钢琴前装装样子
just diddling on the piano.
我现在就装给你们看 玩玩呗
I'll do it right now just for fun.
那才不是你们的呢 不是我的
That's not yours, not mine.
不 真是搞笑
No, it's just ludicrous.
卖录制好的音乐 那才叫唱片
Selling recorded music that's the record.
在过去 那是唱片公司
And that's historically the only thing
唯一在乎的
that a record label records cared about.
直到现在那不再赚钱了
Until that's stopped making money.
如果30STM今天才起步
If Thirty Seconds to Mars started today,
他们甚至只能签个比他们以前
they'd have an even worse deal
更差的合约
than they originally signed
因为签的是所谓的360合约
cause they'd have what they called the 360 deal,
他们得在他们的销售量
they'd have to give away a piece of their merchandising
和他们的巡演中 都分出一份才能签约
and their touring, to get their record deal.
感谢上帝 我们陷入的不是那样的合约
Thank god, we didn't get stuck in one of those deals.
360合约就是 唱片公司涉入到
360 deal is when a record label participates
艺人所有的收入来源中
in all revenue streams of an artist.
典型的有 巡演 经销
Typically touring, merchandise,
还可能有出版 授权许可
could be publishing, licensing opportunities,
资质认证
endorsement opportunities.
这是对现实的直接反映:
It's a direct response to the fact
现在没人能卖掉1000万张专辑了
that no one is selling 10 Million records anymore.
就算你有张热门专辑
Even when you have a big hit,
那也不如过去那样热门
they're not as big as they used to be.
所以 如果你要投资大钱
So, if you are going to invest big money
来捧红一个艺人
in making an artist famous
那你就得多找点圈钱途径了
then, you've got to find more ways to collect.
我处理这样合约时 与他们有过这样一段对话:
The argument I had on one of these deals is they said:
-"好 如果我的委托方有了孩子 并出售了孩子的照片,"
"- Okay, if my client has a baby and sells baby pictures,
"你们要从中分钱吗?"    "那当然了"
do you participate in that? - Well yes."
在过去的一年半里
Over the last 18 months,
前EMI首席执行官
EMI签署的
90% of the deals that have been,
90%的合约
you know, signed by EMI,
都增加了关于权利的条款
have an extended amount of rights,
那就算不是360 你懂的 也是280了...
if they are not 360, they're, you know, 280...
或是什么 之类的 你懂的
or something... Whatever... You know.
所以是的 没错 绝对更多了
So yes, definitely, definitely more.
现在只要是唱片公司都想签360的合约
Everyone wants 360 now as far as labels.
起码大厂牌公司是这样
Majors at least.
独立公司还没完全到360的地步 你懂的
Indies are still not necessarily all 360, you know.
有的是 有的不是
Some do some don't.
那这对艺人有什么好处呢?
So, how does it help an artist?
嗯 没好处
Well, it doesn't.
你得不到任何好处
You've got no leverage,
你只是个新人乐队
you're a band just starting out
不管是大厂牌还是小厂牌都不愿妥协
and neither a label will take this off the table,
那么 你怎么做呢?
so, so what do you do?
对于签了360合约的乐队 嗯
For a band to do a 360 deal, well,
现在他们要把真正的财路都拱手送人了
now, they're turning over their real cash prize.
就是他们巡演所挣的钱
Which is their ability to make money touring
以及巡演时销售的唱片钱
and make money in selling merchandise.
唱片公司在360中 一般是怎么分成呢?
What do labels typically take from a 360?
你知道 这要看...
You know, they vary depending on...
我见过从艺人作品中抽取10%到25%的都有
I've seen as much as 10 to 25% of the artist's piece.
你知道 我还见过有些电视明星
You know, I've seen some of the television
公司抽成甚至高达50% 够疯狂的
star deals go as high as 50%. Pretty crazy.
他们完全抱着这么一种殖民的心态
They've just got this entire plantation mentality,
无论艺人做什么事 钱都应该是他们的
they should own everything that an artist does
我从来都看不惯他们那样
and I've never been comfortable with that.
我真是讨厌那样
I just really hate that.
我上个电影 或是电视节目
I don't need your permission as a record company owner
又不用你唱片公司老总的准许
to go do, you know, things like movies or TV shows.
去你们的吧
Screw you guys!
我们拒绝了他们的最终条款后
After we rejected their last offer,
EMI终于同意跟我们坐下来面谈了
EMI finally agreed to sit down face to face
这样我们可以达成些进展
so, that we could try to work something out.
于是我坐飞机去了纽约
So, I got on a plane and headed to New York.
我们已经僵持很久了
We've been fighting for a long time already
所以我们和唱片公司一直都
and there wasn't a lot of communication going on
没怎么直接联系过
with us and the label directly.
其实根本就没联系过
Let's say virtually none.
外面冷死啦!
It's freezing out!
我从小就喜欢这个城市
I always loved this city ever since I was a kid,
我觉得这地方充满魔力
it's been a magical place for me.
每次来到纽约 我都好兴奋
Every time I come to New York, I'm excited.
很奇怪 感觉这就是我的家一样
I feel like this is my city in a weird way.
比洛杉矶更像家 纽约有某种感觉
More than LA is. There's something about it.
总有惊喜在里面
Always an adventure.
等等 等等 你演过个电影 我知道你!
Wait, wait, you're in a movie. I know you.
你是个名人 是吧
You're famous, aren't you?
呃... 嗯 算是吧...
Erm... Yeah... Kind of...
你在那个很酷的电影里    -还行...
You were in that very cool movie -Sometimes…
里边还有个疯老太太
with the crazy lady.
嗯 是的 <梦之安魂曲>
Yeah, yeah, Requiem for a Dream.
哦天啊 哦天啊 哦天 哦天...   -嗨
Oh my god, oh my god, oh my god... -Hi.
你演过我最喜欢的电影...    -你好吗
You're in my favorite mov…  -How is it going?
哦天啊 我要哭了
Oh my god, I'm gonna cry.
你演过世界上我最喜欢的...
You are in my favorite movie in the whole...
我可喜欢那电影了
I love that movie.
谢谢
Thank you.
我的天 我的天...
Oh my god, oh my god...
你喝的是什么啊?
What's in that drink?
双倍咖啡因吗?
Extra caffeine?
周日是开大会的日子
It's the big meeting Sunday.
在纽约感觉很好
It's was nice to be in New York.
终于有机会离开工作室
I had a chance to get away from the studio
来看一些朋友了
and see some friends.
泰利·理查森
摄影师
但这趟旅行的主要焦点还是这次会谈
But the main focus of the trip was this meeting.
想到终于有机会能谈出点成果 我很兴奋
I was excited that there was a chance to work things out.
但很不幸
Unfortunately...
EMI取消了会议
EMI canceled...
要振作起来 还要很久
It was a long way to go to get stood up,
但我在纽约时
but while I was in New York
听说EMI此时又有大动作了
I heard that there were major changes happening at the label once again and
现在跟EMI达成任何约定
that any possibility of a deal with EMI
都是不可能的
was very unlikely.
噢! 我喜欢那个... 他弹什么呢
Oh! I like that... What he is playing.
我去告诉他我喜欢
Gonna tell them I like that.
你录上那段了吗
Did you record that?
没没 录的是平常的
No, no, the regular one.
啊? 不 我喜欢刚开始那段
Huh? No, no, I like the beginning
你刚才弹的那样
how you just played that.
嗯
Yeah.
它特么的不对劲 因为它变慢了
It's fucking fucking because it's off.
节拍变慢了
It gets off.
你听着节拍就行 你弹的很好
You just got to listen to the click you're good.
等一下
Hold on a second.
好着呢 你跟着节拍弹就行
It's fine. You just got to keep on that beat.
就是节拍的问题
That's the thing.
我跟着节拍弹呢 但它变慢了    -我知道
I'm playing to the click but it's going slower.
-Yeah, I know
但你要跟着节拍走
but you're right with the click
所以挺难的
so it's really hard.
你知道 你得像个机器一样
You know you got to be like a machine.
啊... 人类啊
Ahhhh! Humans!
你听出限制器跟节拍不一样了吗?
You hear that the slicer is not with the click?
对吧?
Right?
要不我来弹弹看?
You want me to play that?
嗯 来吧 你弹
Yeah, go ahead, yeah, please do.
给我证明一下限制器是不是变慢了
Prove me that the slicer is not slowing down!
现在就证明给你看 我的拨片呢?
I'll prove it right now. Where is my goddam pick?
就这样 用他的推弦 剩下的用我的
That's it... Use his pull-off... Use my other thing...
这就行了 在两者之间的效果
It's like the performances between the two
就够好了 所以...
are good enough so...
噢耶! 肘子甩起来 亲!
Oh yeah... The elbow, baby!
甩肘子 喔~~
The fucking elbow! Woo...
我们来了傻逼! 耶!
Here we come motherfucker! Yeah!
咱们还...
What else we...
你就不想 做出点经久不衰的经典?
Don't you just want to make something that lives forever?
前无古人的 伟大的作品?
Something that's phenomenal? Something that's great?
做出些毋庸置疑的东西?
Something that's undeniable?
能触及到每个人的灵魂的?
That touches the core of every person that hears it?
嗯   -你知道吗
Yeah!   -You know.
嗯 你想做出美好的东西
Yeah. You want to make something beautiful,
感人的 能激起波澜的
something moving, something provocative,
纯净又真实的东西
something that's pure and true.
我们正在做
We're doing that.
但愿吧
I hope so.
从始至终 EMI一直想跟我们重订合约
All along EMI had been interested in resigning us.
可问题是 他们一直给我们的
The problem was they kept offering us
都与原本的渣合约大同小异
different variations of the same terrible deal.
我们决定 愿意与EMI重订合约
We decided we would consider resigning with EMI
只要他们愿意正视这一切
if they were willing to make things right.
尤其是只有这样才能
Especially as it would put an end
结束这场野蛮的官司 才能
to this brutal lawsuit and ensure
保证我们的专辑顺利发行
that our album would see the light a day.
所以我们最后又去找了他们一次
So, we went back to them one last time
基本告诉他们:
and basically told them:
"你看 这是我们最终的条款和要求
"Look, these are our final terms and conditions,
"要么签给我们
either meet them
"要么咱就真没什么可谈了"
or there really isn't anything left to talk about."
EMI回应称他们会在24小时之内答复我们
EMI responded saying they'd get back to us in 24 hours
给我们最终的官方答复
with their official final response.
诉讼第180天
有点奇怪 我们还没收到EMI的信
It's a little weird we haven't heard from EMI.
诉讼第182天
还是没EMI的信
No word from EMI.
诉讼第183天
我们在等待一个最终答复
We're waiting for one finale response.
诉讼第185天
啊...
Aaahh...
诉讼第188天
还是...没有!
...And... Nothing!
诉讼第190天
还是没有EMI的信
Still no word from EMI.
诉讼第194天
我们明天肯定能收到
We're gonna hear from them tomorrow.
明天就是了
Tomorrow is the day.
还不赖
It's not bad.
明天 他们又这么告诉我们
Tomorrow, which is what we've been told again,
又一次 又一次 又一次 又一次...
and again, and again, and again, etc.
永远是明天 明天 明天 明天 明天 ...
That it was tomorrow, tomorrow, tomorrow, tomorrow...
上帝啊!
Jesus Christ!
麻烦谁去叫那破狗把嘴闭上
Please someone just shut that fucking dog up.
也许他也很生气?
Maybe he's pissed too?
EMI告诉他 明天给他狗粮
EMI told him he's gonna get his dog food tomorrow.
明天咱就有答复了 明天 明天...
We should have something tomorrow, tomorrow, etc.
感觉就像电影里的人 你懂的
It's like the guy in the movie, you know.
明--天--- 真是可笑
Tooooomorrrrrrow. It's ridiculous.
诉讼第209天
EMI.
卧槽
Holly shit.
EMI投降了
EMI caved.
"我想我们结束了 结 束 了
"I think we are done, capital D.O.N.E.
"要双方都认可 才能发新闻稿
Press release to be mutually approved
"但等签了约那就不是问题了
but that can happened quickly after signing,
"同时请你说服Jared 把他同意的原话发给我们
meanwhile could you get an approved quote from Jared
"然后我们给你发个草案
and we will send you a draft.
"感谢所有人 现在真正的工作开始了"
Thanks to all, now the real work starts."
现在我们得决定
Now we have to decide.
于是Shannon Tomo和我聚在一起商量
So Shannon, Tomo and I got together and debated,
讨论 并作出了决定
discussed and made a decision.
EMI拿着合约 来找我们
EMI came to us and offered us
是我们一直为之争取的合约
the deal we were fighting for.
于是 我们接受了
So, we accepted.
今天真是13号星期五吗?
Is it really Friday the thirteen?
他们也真够勇敢 大胆的 也够愚蠢
It is pretty brave, bold and stupid of them
居然会...跟乐队签合约
to actually make a deal with a band,
即使是我们 连专辑都没听到就签约
even if it's us, without having heard the record.
但同时 他们也知道
But at the same time, they knew
我是无论如何也他妈的不可能
there's not a chance in a fucking hell
给他们做一秒钟的音乐
I was gonna play them a single second of this record.
但这个时候你只能为音乐着想
You have to do what's best for the music at this point.
我觉得现在为了音乐 最好的选择就是与EMI重新签约
I think what's best for the music is resigning with EMI
然后把专辑发出来
and putting a record out.
这张专辑的目标
Your goal on this album
就是让尽可能多的人来买
is to have many people as possible buy that.
你得考虑你的事业
You have to consider your career.
一切都关乎你的事业
It's all about your career.
那 你觉得我们应该怎么做?
So, what do you think we should do?
我觉得你应该签了这个
I think you should sign this thing,
把专辑发了
get your record out there
然后远离法庭 回到工作正轨上
and get back to your career away from courts.
你觉得我们该怎么做
What do you think we should do?
你绝对应该现在就签了这个
You should absolutely sign this deal right now
然后回工作室去 继续工作
and then go back to the studio and keep working.
嗯
Yeah.
真神奇 在我们签约的同时
It's amazing that at the same time we're trying making a deal,
世界也在风起云涌
the world is falling apart.
你看 在过去七八年的时间
Look, you've got seven or eight years
唱片业一直在走向衰败
of the record business just going straight to the dumper
然后 半年多之前
and then, six great months ago,
全世界都跟唱片业一样了
the rest of the world went with the record business.
现在一切都在衰退
Everything is in the dumper now.
那 我怎么没有庆祝胜利的感觉?
So, why don' I feel like we should be celebrating?
因为这是唱片业啊
Because it's the record business,
唱片行业里真是
there's really nothing to celebrate
没什么好庆祝的
about the record business,
因为这是个夕阳产业
because it's a dying business.
尤其在国际层面上
And especially on an international level
你们的唱片要有70%卖到国际市场
where you guys are gonna sell 70% of your records
因为还是海外市场卖的好
cause more records still sell overseas.
你知道 你们能拿到这样的很不错了
You know, you gotta have one of these, guys.
这是你们不打官司能拿到的最好的了
And this is the one you get without a lawsuit.
Jared 你很理想主义
Jared, you were very idealistic and
你想把唱片业的弊端都写下来
you wanted to write the wrongs of the record business
但问题在于
and you're not gonna have your chance to see it before
在它曝出音乐界的腐败
it shines a light on the corruption of the music business
或是搞垮音乐界之前 不过它本来也快垮掉了
or take it down, but it's going down anyway.
你根本就没机会看到它
That's the problem.
有时候真的很难停止斗争    -难多了
It's hard to stop fighting sometimes.   -Much tougher
你怎么停止斗争呢?
How do you stop fighting?
你怎么能呢?
How can you do that?
因为他们都被炒了
Because they're all fired.
这个 我说一句 是一份合同
This, by the way, is one contract.
诉讼第211天
深呼吸啊哥们
Take a deep breath, man.
我们的协议是我们非常中意的
The deal that we made was a very favorable one
比三十秒上火星以前的好的多得多
and a much better deal that Thirty Second to Mars had.
诉讼是为了达到
The goal of the litigation is to accomplish
你提起诉讼时的目的
whatever goal you got the litigation for.
我觉得艺人们
I don't think that the court room
还是别上法庭的好
is a really good place for artists to be.
我觉得他们最好还是呆在录音室里
I think they're better off in the studios.
真正的战役是 争分夺秒
The real battle is the clock starts.
你们赶紧把专辑做完
You got to finish the record.
嗯... 对
Mmmm... Yeah.
工作回到正轨
Try to get this show on the road.
没有借口
And no excuses.
你们把这首歌做完了吗?
Have you finished with this song yet?
于是 与EMI的新合同规定
So, the new contract with EMI says
我们还有三周的时间来完成
that we have three weeks left to finish.
争分夺秒
The clock is ticking.
你们知道有何种方法
Is there any kind of methodology that you know about
可以提高 我们剩下这几天的产量吗?
to increase the productivity of the remaining days we have here?
对了 Guy Hands今天下台了
So, Guy Hands stepped down today.
哦 是吗?
Oh, did he?!
这绝对是又出了幺蛾子
That definitely means there's some shit shifting
又有变化了
and changing around.
重大新闻 花旗集团接管了
Breaking news, Citigroup taking ownership
国际领头的音乐公司
of one of the world's leading music companies.
葛涵思的泰丰资本报告
百代EMI亏损17.6亿美元
泰丰资本的Guy Hands 收购EMI时
Guys Hands is from Terra Firma, acquired EMI
用了高额借贷的方式
with a lot of debt and the numbers
泰丰资本报亏 免除EMI一半债务
其数目是惊人的
never made a lot of sense and so
现在花旗集团接管了EMI
here we are with Citigroup taking control of EMI.
神奇的痛苦之旅
花旗集团接管音乐巨头
泰丰资本奋力地掌控EMI...十分丢脸
EMI的业绩下滑和支离破碎
The decline and demolishment of EMI
葛涵思失去商业嗅觉了吗？
是21世纪的一大悲哀的失败
is a sad 21st century story of failure.
泰丰资本的葛涵思从EMI辞职
泰丰资本总裁葛涵思下台
他经营的是一整个
He was running a whole company
他一点也不了解 完全不会经营的公司
that categorically he was incapable of running.
显然最后它变成了一个大错误
Obviously it turned out to be a tremendous mistake
收购的时机也不对
bought at the wrong time.
他真的相信他能使之改头换面
He really believed he was gonna transform it
然后再卖掉 我认为他不会想到
and then sell it. I don't think he thought,
他会拥有它 然后输掉它
that he would own it and then, lose it.
花旗集团接管EMI 免除其债务
EMI现在 就是花旗集团账上的一颗毒瘤
What EMI now is, it's a bump sitting on Citibank
等着被从账目里清除掉
balance sheet, waiting to be removed from their balance sheet
然后被卖给下一个倒霉鬼
and sold to the next sucker.
想把唱片公司扭亏为盈 可没有一招制敌的
There is no killer app to turn around a record company.
得是慢慢地 耐心地处理 需要很长时间
It has to be done slowly and patiently and it takes time.
抛弃艺人需要时间
It takes time to break artist,
签约艺人需要时间
it takes time to sign artist,
找到合适的高管来介入 更需要时间
and it takes time to get the right executives in.
我觉得Guy是... 我不会当他面这么说
I think that Guy, and I wouldn't say this to his face...
嗯... 他是个很精明的人
Hum... He is a very bright guy
只是不幸地 被舆论所误导
who unfortunately had the popular misimpression
以为音乐产业里全是白痴和小偷
that the music business is populated by idiots and thieves.
那些我们不是没有
We've got our fair share of them,
但是行业里也有很多聪明的好人
but there's a lot smart, good people in the business.
音乐公司EMI为泰丰资本
带来17亿英镑资产减值损失
总裁葛涵思创下行业纪录
只是因为那家伙是个亿万富翁
Just because the guy is a billionaire
而且他在别的行业里赚了很多钱
and he's made a bunch of money in other businesses,
你知道 我们业内有很多人
you know... We have a long list of people
作为外行人进入音乐界
from outside the music business that have come
最后毁的不成样子
and entered the business and left it in ruins.
而他是他们中间栽得最大的
And he is the biggest fool of all of them.
葛涵思拒绝了本片的采访
知道我怎么想的吗?
You know what I think?
怎么
What?
我想我们今晚就能做完这首歌
I think we're gonna finish this song tonight.
挺不错
Pretty good one.
就这样吧
Let's call it finished.
喔! 击掌! 耶!
Woo! High five! Yeah!
喔 来啊 别让我举着手啊少年们!
Woo! Come on! Don't leave me hanging, boys!
音乐界的未来是未知的
The future of the music business is unknown.
这让一些人兴奋
That's what makes it exciting to some
也让另一些人害怕
and really scary to others.
因为人们可以在自己家里录歌
Because people can record in their houses
然后在一夜间发布出来
and distribute overnight.
我相信音乐可以
I believe that music can reclaim
收复其主流媒体的地位
its space as the driving medium.
总有变化 有发展
There is change, there's evolution.
如果你不跟上变化 你就得死
If you don't ride the change, you die.
Jared总是开玩笑说 等哪天某个孩子写了首歌
Jared always jokes that some kid is gonna write a song
然后他把它做好
and he's gonna figure it out
然后一支单曲就卖掉几百万张
and is gonna sell hundreds millions copies of a single
全靠他自己 然后他会赚个十亿美元
by himself and he's gonna make a Billion Dollars
他会说 "操你们的,
and he's gonna say: "fuck you,
"老子不需要你们(唱片公司)"  然后那时
I don't need you." And then,
就会是新的开始
that's gonna be the new beginning.
声破天(知名流媒体音乐服务软件)
首席执行官 创始人
人们现在听的音乐
People listen to more music now
比以前听的多很多
than ever before, from a bigger
听到的艺人也多很多
diversity of artists.
所以我觉得文化上 我们的处境更好了
So, I think culturally, we are in a much better place.
在我看来 我真的认为
I look at it and I actually think
我们算是进入了音乐的黄金时代
that we are at sort of entering the golden age for music.
我每这样想就很高兴 如今的下一代人群
I love the idea that we may, in this next generation,
不再生活在 可能性有限的世界里
not be living in a world of the possibility of,
你懂的 成功标准很高
you know, being successful is,
你不用成为迈克尔杰克逊 麦当娜
that you have to be Michael Jackson, Madonna,
Prince Lady Gaga那样的人 而如今是
Prince, Lady Gaga but, that actually like:
做音乐人的梦想离人们更近了
the dream of being musician means,
你完全可以以之为生 联系大众
you can just make a living and connect with people
专心做你的音乐 不必去找一份你讨厌的工作
and make your music and not have to have a job you hate.
音乐永远不死
Music will never die.
它永远会带动这个行业
It will always drive industry,
会带动创新
it will always drive innovation,
每个人都能得到
it will be always be available to everyone
每个人也都想得到
and everyone always is going to want it.
而评论界怎么说
It doesn't really matter what the critic says
或是当权者怎么说 真不太重要
or the gatekeeper says,
真的 在如今这个时代的音乐界
really, in this day and age of the music industry,
新的当权者 是粉丝们
the new gatekeepers are the fans.
如果你有五百万听众免费下载你的专辑
If you have 5 Million people downloading your album for free,
那你仍然触及了五百万人
that's still 5 Million people you've touched.
我觉得 那就有比钱更贵重的价值
and has a value to me that's far greater than money.
*<全面开战>  <全面开战>!*...
This Is War! This Is War!...
三十秒上火星乐队的新专辑全面开战售出了近二百万张
他们的巡演门票在世界各地售罄
2011年11月11日  花旗集团拆分了百代EMI
将其售给了其他唱片公司 (注: 环球和索尼)
据EMI称 三十秒上火星乐队仍然欠之170万美元
三十秒上火星仍然未得到唱片销售利润
多少人买了
How many people have a copy
我们的新专辑<全面开战>?
of our new record "This is War?"
多少人是从网上下载的盗版?
And how many people stole that copy off the internet?
*谢谢观赏 请购买正版~*
Vyrt和Amazon有售 -Ericartman
导演
巴塞洛缪·卡宾斯